Creations.
Creatures.
Minecraft.
I'm just saying shit at this point.
What's going on?
It's time for some good old Minecraft.
I'm not gonna lie.
I am kind of addicted to Kerbal Space Program as well.
But I want to play some Minecraft.
Just a bit of Minecraft is always good for the soul, isn't it?
I guess the creative juice is flowing.
Man.
How dare you, Oliver?
I shit myself.
Oh, I'm sorry about that, Julia.
Get some diapers.
I have no advice.
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
It wasn't even that loud.
I tried to do it quietly.
I tried to, you know, jump scare you, but quietly.
Add a crank to the waiting menu.
No, but you guys represent the crank.
You know?
You are the crank.
KSP is gonna be probably next stream.
Not this one.
We're playing Minecraft today.
Yeah, sure.
Fine excuses.
I mean... I think it's beautiful that you guys represent the crank.
You know?
There's something about that.
You're the crankers.
Exactly.
Your name starts with O.
Isn't that strange?
I guess so.
But is it really that strange?
I did not see the Minecraft live, but I heard from people that it has a lot of hype updates.
So that's cool.
First time being here.
What's up, Maymits?
Good to see you.
And Phyrix, as well.
Or Phyrixis, underscore.
I love doing lines of crank.
Oh yeah?
That's cool.
I showed my mom your last KSP stream.
She loved it.
What?
She did?
That's crazy.
Why would you show her my stream?
What compelled you to do such a thing?
I feel like I'm not family friendly.
I say bad words, you know?
And I make sexual jokes and stuff.
It's not, it's not, uh, fitting.
Because she likes space.
Well, okay, in that case.
I guess that makes sense.
Family friendly streamer.
No, I'm not.
I'm actually exactly opposite.
I am not a family friendly streamer at all.
Oliver, she's a mom.
Okay, what does that mean?
What?
Uh-huh.
Have you thought or heard about the journey map mod?
I have neither thought or heard about it.
Hotu Stone!
I downloaded Twitch on my phone specifically so I'd get a notification for Oliver's stream.
Awesome.
Thank you, H2O Stone.
I'm glad it works.
Some people are saying that the Twitch notifications aren't working.
What's up, all the new chatters?
Flawless Minecraft.
Meepcat8.
How you doing?
Moms do love Oliver.
He's literally mom liver.
I don't know if I like that sentence.
That's kind of horrible.
Hey, what's up, Diego?
I'm doing fantastic.
How's it going with you?
Are you dying of heat right now?
Or what?
What's the humidity like?
What's the pressure?
Everything going right?
One minute and 30 seconds of ads?
Well, there you go.
Enjoy the ads.
I will now start 700 minutes of ads.
I will start 700 minutes of ads in 4 minutes.
Get ready.
I don't even think I can do that.
If I wanted to.
700 minutes of ads.
So stupid.
Oh my god.
Now it's much better.
The mosquitoes are awful though.
Maybe, I mean, are you one of the unlucky ones where the mosquitoes just go straight for you?
Because some people I know, the mosquitoes don't care about them.
Like, I'm the one who gets bitten all the time, you know?
They like to suck my blood, but my friends, no.
They ignore them.
Maybe you're one of the lucky ones.
Hey, what's up, Wassong Galsh?
What's up, Pro Twitch?
I'm sorry, that's the only thing I think of when I read WSG.
Oliver, please check my next comment.
I will not.
I will ignore your next comment.
In two minutes, we have 700 minutes of ads.
Get ready.
It's coming in.
Brace yourselves.
And the ads will be completely irrelevant to your interests.
Please just do 600 minutes.
Okay.
For you, I'll do 600.
600 babies!
Where's that from?
Isn't that the energy drink commercial?
Wait, is it 600 babies or is it 3,000 babies?
Something like that.
I will not do what you told me to.
I am my own person.
Hey, Oliver.
I think you're so cool and sometimes binge you for long periods of time.
Enjoy your day, big dog.
That's funny.
I also binge watch you.
But in real life.
I'm outside sometimes.
Optimal peak.
It's me.
The rustling in the bushes?
That's me.
The sound late at night?
It's me.
It's not me.
I'm kidding.
What block do you like?
Andeside or Diorite?
Well, it depends.
If it's normal Minecraft, definitely andeside.
But if it's create, then definitely andeside.
Are you my dad who left for milk?
No.
I wish I was.
I'm on episode 22, so no spoilers.
Okay.
Then I'm not gonna tell you about all the flying machines I made and how we went to the center of the planet.
And we obtained something called Unobtainium.
And there's a scientist with us who apparently is full of himself.
And, uh...
Holy shit, I'm spoilering something here.
What is that movie?
There's a movie.
About that.
What did you do today at work?
I mean, I need more vlogs.
I am not working at my work anymore.
This is my work right now.
I wake up and I play a video game.
And then I stop playing video games and then I go cuddle my cat.
And that's my day.
Can I call you olive oil?
Please do, because I love olive oil.
Olive oil is the best oil.
Change my mind.
Sounds nice.
It is nice.
It is very nice.
Why don't you stop astroing the physics?
Because this now became a thing.
And as much as I love physics, I love video games more.
And I got to jump at the opportunity, right?
The only thing I wish is that I actually had more of a...
What's the word?
You know when you say you have a sex drive?
There's a word for sex drive.
But what is the game drive that you have?
You know?
Like, I wish I had more game drive.
Because I would love to play more games.
Like, I could force myself to play more, but it's not going to be as enjoyable to watch, right?
Passion?
Eh, maybe.
Motivation?
Yeah, but motivation makes it sound like it's a chore.
It's a chore to do, which it isn't.
You know?
On some days, you just don't feel like playing.
So it sounds kind of dumb, but for this work I'm doing here, it's actually not a good idea to stream on days where I don't feel like playing.
Yes, I'd probably make some money on that day from streaming it, but it's not going to be enjoyable to watch.
I'm going to be miserable playing it because I don't want to play, and then people don't want to watch.
And then it's actually a long-term bad investment to do, you know?
It's weird.
You know what, you know what I wish though?
I wish all of you loved World of Warcraft as much as you love Minecraft, Outer Wilds, whatever else you enjoy watching me play.
Because World of Warcraft, I could play that every day, every day.
I could play 12 hours every day.
That's like, that's the only way to get me to play fully full-time.
While still having fun.
You don't understand how people like WoW?
Found the non WoW player.
Well, personally, I decided not to do it.
Because I, you know, I am a person who values the lives of these animals in the game.
So now I have made a nice enclosure for them, and I will not be automatically killing them.
I'm going to be manually killing them, so I can look them in the fucking eye when I do it.
When I stab them and slice them up and watch their entrails come out.
I want to feel the last bit of life, you know, fade.
Nah, I'm not evil, I'm just pretending to be.
I'm actually kind of not evil.
I'm kind of mild, you know?
Stop that!
It's time.
For...
Wait, did my...
Dude, my Minecraft crashed again.
Okay, so if you have Minecraft open for extended periods, and it's minimized, then the game will crash.
This is my investigation, this is what I have found out.
Every time.
Or maybe it's...
If I open Minecraft and then I start streaming, maybe that crashes the game.
Is that what's happening?
I wonder.
Maybe that's what's happening.
12 herbs and spices, is what it says.
21 mods!
I'm ready.
Guys, it's kind of...
It's kind of huge, because we got so much netherite.
In the bag.
This is the big development from last time.
I had such an incredible time mining all that netherite.
And it sounds weird to say, but...
It's like...
Yeah, the mining itself is not that fun, but when you find things, then it's really fun.
And I found a lot, which means I had a lot of fun.
And we even got our thingy back.
I think.
We got the contraption back somewhere.
Now I just have to remember where I put it.
The contraption is here somewhere.
Oh, that's right!
We also have an infected villager here.
That we need to cure.
So that we can actually get on breaking.
So we can fly!
And I still did not figure out...
Fucking hell, dude.
How am I not, like, aware of this?
Also, I have all these.
Lowstone compass.
This one is going to be my actual compass that points to home.
Yep.
I will never get lost again.
I mean, of course, unless I die.
But I'm not gonna die again.
What is the plan even right now?
I mean, the ultimate plan is to make trains, right?
That's, like, the ultimate goal here.
Which means we needed a lot of tracks.
And to get tracks, I needed something else.
There was a whole, you know, line of reasoning last time.
Hey, I actually learned my lesson about this.
Remember last time?
I got all the things, and I didn't die.
Yeah.
Very good.
Now.
Where did I leave that digging machine?
Oh, I remember now.
I destroyed it.
This is actually the one.
Remember, I accidentally, instead of using my wrench on it, I clicked on it.
So it got destroyed.
Which sucks.
So we're gonna make a new one.
A much better one.
We have 25 drills.
Dude, we're gonna...
Oof.
We're gonna make a huge digging machine.
Perhaps I'll even make more drills.
25 is not enough.
Iron ingots and alloys.
Okay, I don't have a lot of that.
Um...
I mean...
Andesite alloy.
Let me see here.
Andesite.
That's six more.
That takes us to 31.
And...
I think I have more somewhere.
Oh yeah, this one.
Iron ingots.
That one.
I also did need these for something else, but, uh...
We can always get that from Sink as well.
That means nine digging machines.
And alloys, I believe I have a lot of.
Eh...
Kinda.
God, I love this song right here.
This is like...
Mmm...
So good.
Nuggets and andesite.
I think I have all that.
Andesite.
Show me where you are.
I may have used it all.
Okay, we don't need that many drilling machines.
I think it's okay if we don't use all of them.
Right?
I'll make as much as I can.
Uh, andesite casing, which I have.
Now we can make drill.
Four.
Okay, twenty-nine.
Not bad.
I like that.
And to make it, we also needed some glue.
And you know what?
Guys!
Let's actually make a pretty digging machine this time.
Because the old one was ugly.
I really didn't like the look of it.
What is happening here?
Someone's taking damage.
It was not these guys.
It was someone else.
Somewhere.
Oh, well.
Whatever.
Okay, so to make a really pretty digging machine...
Um...
Also, I had something in here.
Woo!
That's a lot.
I need chests.
In fact, we can add even more chests.
Why are we being so...
Conservative, you know?
Why not go all out?
There we go.
Seven chests.
Actually, we should probably make six.
Just to keep it looking nice.
And...
So we have this one.
So that's gonna be connected to a...
Finger.
Actually, we need two fingers.
Right?
One of them has...
Tracks.
Uh...
The other one has...
Stone.
Or...
Insert whatever you need to make the bridge.
So those two things.
And then we need glass.
That's right.
I actually had this on my...
Newest machine.
I just...
Did air quotes with my fingers.
You couldn't see that, but I did.
And...
That was the machine I forgot I had.
Right?
The one that also had a furnace.
But now we have that.
So everything's Gucci.
I need tracks.
Tracks.
And...
Actually, I should probably make more tracks.
Because I keep running out.
I think I need iron for that?
Uh...
What's it called?
Rail.
Oh my...
Dude.
Really?
That's a lot.
Why am I all...
Okay, hold on.
I feel like we need some kind of way to...
Dude, imagine having like...
Automatic iron creation.
Can we like do anything?
Nah.
Oh my god.
I am constantly running low on iron.
And the worst part is...
The digging machine is not actually gonna help me with that.
Because last time I did it, I got almost no iron.
Like targeted iron mining is much better, you know?
Oh, speaking of targeted iron mining.
From now on, it's actually more efficient...
To mine with Silk Touch.
Why you ask?
Because this machine right here...
Is gonna give us more iron when we do it.
Yeah.
The thing is though, I don't have a good pickaxe yet.
With Silk Touch.
It'll suck.
Okay.
Time to make the thing.
Let's make it over here.
It needs to be pretty.
A whole new design.
Wait, I guess we need the thingy.
The little...
What's it called?
The assembly.
Assemble.
That one.
And a switch.
So this one first.
I'm gonna make this in record time.
Now, glass.
The only thing I need to remember now...
Is exactly where this goes.
I think this one needed to go one higher.
Because it's placing something in this slot here.
Whereas the one that makes the bridge is one slot down, you know?
So we actually remove this.
Whatever.
There we go.
No.
Really wish it wouldn't do that.
Actually, wait a sec.
That's the trick.
To make it not pick up anything else.
Wait.
We actually do want this.
That's what we want.
Much better.
Holy shit.
Okay.
And then here.
Oh, Jesus.
Please leave me alone.
How are you even here?
Are there not lights?
Lights.
Oh, there's a light there.
Maybe like here.
Okay.
Should be good.
Okay, dude.
Can you please fuck off?
How the...
How are these people here?
I don't understand anything.
Are my lights not good enough?
Oh my god.
And now we got Enderman 2.
This feels like playing Terraria right now.
Except...
The shitty music isn't here.
Come on.
Hey, actually, it's not that bad.
Because I kind of need a little bit of experience to hit 30.
I'm almost there.
Bro!
Fucking children.
Ruining my day.
What are they doing?
So confused by this.
Oh.
Okay, finally.
Rest up, king.
Are we good?
Okay, you're burning.
Bastard.
Okay, let's try and figure this out.
There we go.
Leave me alone.
Um...
I guess we should have sort of a...
I'm trying to think.
I guess it would be dirt.
Yeah, let's just take some dirt.
And you know what?
I'm pretty sure if I put a chest on top of it, it's just going to take from the chest.
Because things just happen, you know, magically when you...
When you...
Oh, I already have chests.
Things already happen magically, right?
When they're in the contraption.
Dirt!
Give me, like, three stacks.
So now we do this.
Dup!
Now it can only pick up dirt.
And...
Uh...
I guess it depends how I want to shape this thing.
Dude, I still hate the look of it.
Like, it's ugly, isn't it?
It's not pretty.
It's disgusting looking.
I would love to make it look better.
I don't know how we should do that.
Maybe more glass.
And again, we also need chests somewhere.
Where everything is going to end up in.
I guess the chests can go on the side.
Like...
But then I'm going to block this, which I probably need to have access to at certain points.
I guess in the back would be ideal, right?
Stuff like this.
Oh my god, it's not even aligned.
Looks like a face.
Two eyes and a mouth.
I don't mind that.
That's decent.
Now...
Oh, wait a sec.
Do we even need...
This?
Not bad.
Wait, how did I run out of chests?
Oh...
For some reason I thought like six chests were six full-sized ones.
That's wrong.
That's not how that works.
Give me...
Oh my god, I don't have any wood?
Really?
Oh shit.
I guess we gotta crank it.
Cranking time.
And then a saw.
Just a quick cranking session.
And you know what?
We can crank all the shitty trees that we hate.
Like this one.
I hate that tree.
Here we go.
God, that was loud.
Almost hurt my ears.
It's like a bunch of, you know, waves just constructively amplifying each other into infinity.
Because they're all breaking at the same time, you know?
Not sure if that's actually how that works, but...
In this game.
What did I just destroy?
Oak.
Okay.
So we do another oak.
I need a disgusting oak.
They're all non-disgusting.
Oh, we have one over here.
Also, maybe we finish this today.
I wanna make a little harbor.
Oh, that's...
Oh, I can't wait to destroy this.
This is gonna feel amazing.
Oh, yeah.
I'm taking this too.
No, don't you float away from me.
Wow, they really fell far.
Look at this.
I never understood why people in real life yell Simba when a tree falls.
It's like the guy from Lion King.
Maybe it's related somehow.
Oh, wait a minute.
They had Lion King after they invented tree felling.
How does that make sense?
Hmm.
Yeah, they probably fell some trees before them.
What do I not need?
Yeah.
Don't make that.
Okay, now we got wood.
Actually, I hate this.
Turn it into better wood.
Actually, I would say planks are inferior to logs.
What do you think?
Do you agree?
I need the workbench.
This, by the way, is a desire path.
When I jump from here to there...
You know how in real life, there's these desire paths everywhere?
Where instead of the preordained paths, people choose to walk their own little shortcuts.
That's one of them.
22 chests!
Oy!
Oh, you know what we should do?
We should...
Wait.
I wonder...
If we can place brown toolboxes...
That get filled up automatically.
Because look.
They stack in 256.
I feel like I should do that.
Or at least try.
There's a chance it may not work.
But...
We're gonna save that experiment for a little bit.
I guess I can try it now, real quick.
Nah, I would have to put the diggers in front.
I don't want to do that.
Yet.
It's not time.
Da-da-da-da-da.
Da-da-da-da-da-da.
Fixed.
Okay, now for the digging machines.
How do I want these arranged?
Let me think.
So I guess...
I guess it would just be...
We can maybe go one higher.
Like here.
There.
Obviously there.
Like, this design is...
Not changing.
Like, there's no way around this design right here.
It needs to be flat and ugly out front.
That's how it works.
See, I actually like this one.
We can even do one more on each side.
And it's a good amount.
And we have one left.
That's pretty.
I think that's pretty.
And maybe we can even do something on the back to make it even prettier.
Maybe some kind of decoration or...
You know.
So, Create has a bunch of little funny decorations you can use.
Such as...
What is it called again?
The little weirdo thingies.
These ones.
A bracket, I think?
Yes.
Wooden bracket and metal...
Okay, we're not doing metal bracket.
Planks and sticks.
I got them both.
Get rid of this.
Oh, oh, wait.
I turned everything into...
Chests, didn't I?
See, why did I do that?
I didn't need to turn that many into chests.
That was total overkill.
I don't understand why I did that.
That sounded like a creeper just now.
There we go.
Oh, alloy.
Oh, I just used them all, didn't I?
Ah, man.
Bummer.
But hey.
What if we put, like, shafts on them?
Mega shaft machine.
Is that ugly?
We could also...
You know, we could also cover that up.
What about glass?
Glass is what holds it together.
I like it.
I may not like it.
That's good.
Now, for the boxes here.
Yes.
And then we need something to hold onto the boxes up top.
What would that be?
Oh, also, check this out.
Little modification.
We are going to have a chest.
Wait, what?
Did I put a glass here?
What the?
And then inside these chests, we're going to put dirt?
So they're going to fall into that, right?
Maybe.
But then again, I mean, these ones are going to do the same.
So this is actually kind of wasted, I guess.
Yeah, actually.
Just realized.
They're going to draw from any chest that is, you know, attached to this mechanism.
So instead, I'm just going to add more chests.
Up here.
Maybe even here.
Is that disgusting?
I feel like it's kind of disgusting, but it's like a needed disgusting.
We're not done.
We're adding more.
Okay.
Let's add more here.
Man, that's a lot of chests.
I feel like this may be overkill.
You know how when you're at a buffet in real life, and you put, like, a lot of food on your plate?
So much so that you're almost embarrassed?
That's how I feel right now.
I feel like I'm adding too much.
The fuck is that sound?
Oh, it's...
Oh!
You are making my dog growl.
Get in bath.
That's right.
Get washed, nerd.
Okay, so that's the look of it so far.
I actually kind of like it.
It's, like, a little industrial and modern at the same time.
So I wonder if we can make it better, even.
Maybe connect these via...
something.
It's a time for the flapjacks.
We're gonna flapjack this?
Also, let me just double-check the functionality is working.
So we have the diggers in front.
We have the path layer here.
We got the rail layer there.
They're gonna do their thing.
They're gonna draw whatever is in these boxes, right?
So I could even say in this one, I put in...
What do you call it?
Oh, wait a sec!
I just remembered a discovery I made.
You can have this thing indefinitely put down rails.
Oh, wait a minute!
I had a whole thing going!
It just occurred to me!
I need the... this one!
Fucking hell!
I forgot how I did it.
How did I do that last time?
Oh, no!
I have to redesign this!
Maybe.
No, I guess I put this in the back.
It was like this.
No, the other way.
I guess we needed glass, then.
Like that.
It looks weird.
But we... we gotta connect this, by the way.
Uh, I'm actually gonna go grab some...
Some of these andesite casings.
Because I think they look nice.
This is just for visual...
Beautifulness.
And it'll be beautiful.
Now it looks like it's actually being sucked up here.
You see what I mean?
And now these bastards are back!
Can't get a moment's...
Rest.
Okay.
Then I wanna connect along here.
So that should...
Work.
I'm trying to think why it wouldn't.
It may have to go back one more.
Because right now, it's technically trying to grab what's in front of it.
And what's in front of it is the...
Cart.
No.
What's in front of it is the track underneath the cart.
Which means that the...
Cart will start to...
Not work anymore.
Yeah, fuck.
Shit.
I gotta move it back.
Like here.
I mean...
That will work.
Oh.
And then the tech I discovered was that...
If you have rails in one of these boxes...
In the first slot...
And you do it just right.
Then it will...
Uh...
Continuously pick them up.
Put them in.
And have them go through here.
That's how that's...
Unless...
Hold on.
Unless because now I actually...
Uh...
Filtered this one to be only rails.
Maybe it doesn't have to be...
In the first slot anymore.
Oh.
I think I'm improving on the last design.
Right now.
The only thing that's worrying me...
Is that this thing is technically not connect...
Oh, it is connected by these.
Okay, okay.
That's good.
Now comes the hardest part.
The gluing.
This is just some of the most...
Unintuitive shit I've ever seen in my life.
So it's going to be difficult.
Okay.
And then here.
I'm going to bring that all the way there.
I guess.
Yo, wait a sec.
Nah, nah, nah.
Ah, that's good.
And then we do from here.
To there.
Wait.
Here.
There.
And this one.
All the way to here.
Ah.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
This thing...
Oh, shit.
I don't think this one...
I need...
Oh.
I gotta redo it.
Then what?
This one.
There.
This one there.
And then this one...
Not...
Ooh.
Almost fucked it up.
Yeah.
And then...
This one...
There.
This one here.
And this one...
There.
Oh.
We're missing something here.
Oh, but I can't from...
You know what I wish I could do?
I wish I could separate them like this.
So that...
And then just click a button and everything that's currently touching in this thing...
Is now the machine.
Isn't that a much better idea for this?
Wait, get rid of this.
Now we need glue.
We have some empty space with glue.
I don't know if that's good.
Maybe that's bad.
Oh.
Oh, no!
Okay, we're fine.
I guess we take that one...
And bring it down...
I forgot whether or not I needed the mine cart as part of this.
I'm gonna say yes.
Okay, that's...
That's it.
We got it.
Now.
Lock.
Nice.
And now...
What the fuck is that?
Why does the grass look like that?
Oh.
What?
It's...
Pulling the grass!
Look at that!
Huh?
Oh, wait a sec.
Are we...
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I understand.
Maybe.
I think I get it.
It's because I...
I accidentally glued the bottom part.
Oh.
I see.
Can you please destroy that?
This.
There we go.
That's how we do it.
Now.
Yes.
Okay, okay, okay.
Now.
I wish I could push from back here, but I can't.
Okay, let's...
Let's see now.
How do I know, uh...
Oh, shit.
Uh-oh, wait.
It's not putting down...
Why is it not...
Is that because I just didn't give it some?
Now I gave it some.
Wait a minute.
Let's say I only gave it one.
Right?
Okay.
Um...
I only gave it one, and then I put some in here.
Let's put it, like, there.
Let me see how many tracks there are.
23.
Let's give it one.
Let's just...
Fill this up with some...
Random crap.
Let's put this, like, there.
There you go.
I guess I should probably...
Grab a little dirt.
Oh, the other way.
The other way.
Oh, wait.
Is it working?
I guess it's working since it's not going down, right?
Yeah.
Hey, it's working.
It's working.
Wonderful.
And the dirt is being grabbed from wherever.
Yes.
Oh, it's beautiful.
The ultimate design.
It's the ultimate design.
Now, to make this even more ultimate, what we could do is add hoppers in between these chests.
So that everything always flows to the back.
Yo.
That's actually a great idea.
That way I don't have to go manually check everyone.
I empty one and the rest falls in.
Maybe that's over-engineering.
Because, also, I need a lot of hoppers for that.
And you know what that takes?
Iron.
I don't have iron.
Or maybe I have some other method.
I got four hoppers.
Actually, that is probably already enough.
But what I want to do, I need four on each side.
Yeah.
That's already good, I think.
Let's just put that bad boy here.
Oh, we need a track for that.
Oh, wait.
Oh!
Wait a sec!
We forgot the most important part.
It needs to drive on its own, dude.
Why does it look like...
What is that...
What is this wood thing in there?
And what is this weird slap?
Look at the slap!
How can she slap?
I don't understand this.
Yeah, I need this one.
Oh, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't do that.
Get in there.
There we go.
We gotta make this self-driving, bro.
This was, like, the whole thing.
And we also need coal.
It can only run on coal.
Doesn't work on others.
Well, maybe there's some that work, but haven't found them yet.
Time for coal.
And, you know what?
It will even self-fuel.
If we find coal during our dig.
It's actually amazing.
Wow.
But let's just give it some start coal.
Oh!
Six ironing, it's sweet!
Very good.
Like finding some candy you forgot you had in the closet.
I'll take more coal.
Okay, this should be fine for now.
Put that in there.
Huh?
Oh, that's weird.
Wait, there's a limit?
It can only have five?
Or, like, whatever, how many that was?
Seven?
Does the coal stay in there?
Wait, where did my coal go?
I am Confucius Maximus.
See, now...
Hmm.
Is it going in here or something?
Okay, I actually...
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
It works!
We got a crazy digging machine now.
Let's go use it.
Let's see if we can find an amazing spot.
And, hold on.
We also want to dig tunnels for this here anyway.
Right?
That's what I started to do last time, but then I ran out of tracks and all that.
So, we're going to do this.
We're going to do some manual digging here.
No, I guess we're not going to do manual digging.
That's the whole point.
We're going to use this.
Ah, but we need to put on there first.
And I think it's also too far forward right now.
I need to remember the exact dimensions of this so I don't forget it.
So, if I put...
Oh.
Right.
So, it's like...
One, two...
Three ahead...
And one, two...
Three back?
Oh my god.
It's actually wonderful.
How come it's not going?
Yeah.
Where did my coal go?
It...
My coal is gone.
Unless it put it somewhere.
You've got to be shitting me.
Um...
Maybe...
Okay, that's...
A mystery.
Also, something I don't like is that it's actually doing this...
As well.
When it's going.
But maybe there's no way around that.
Dude, there's something going on.
Why can't I...
Funny how this one is being filled up and it's over...
Also, why are there 13 rails there?
So, apparently, if you put coal in the machine...
And you disassemble it, you lose the coal.
Unless it's, like, back here somewhere.
I can't believe that.
That can't be the case.
There's something going on.
That's horrible.
Keep that one.
Keep the lever, too.
These are essential.
Don't need this right now.
Where's my saw?
There.
Yo, you could even put a...
Yo.
If you put a saw...
Ah, but that's not going to work.
Because sometimes...
Actually, is it going to work?
You destroy the first two.
And then...
At some point, you're going to destroy the last.
And then they will fill all the trees.
Yo.
You can make a pretty cheap...
Forest eradicator.
With just saws at the bottom.
Bro.
Because...
Let's say there's a 2x2 tree, right?
You dig these two...
It's not going to be destroyed.
But as soon as these two are gone...
The whole tree falls.
Not bad!
Not bad.
Insane tech here.
Anyway, um...
I guess we gotta go find some coal.
Can't really do much without that.
I don't have any coal anywhere.
Shit.
I guess I can just push it...
Until we find coal.
That's the whole...
Brilliant design behind it.
Hold on.
I need to look at this guy while I eat it.
That's right.
That's what's going to happen...
If you keep standing on those tracks...
One of these days...
Uh...
I guess we just go along here.
Yeah, just push.
No!
Why are you like this?
Do I have to pull out my assembler?
Ow!
You don't want to be standing on that...
When you plop it down.
Oh, shit.
But now...
Now it needs power.
There we go.
Off you go.
We can go faster.
At some point, it's gonna hit some coal.
And it's gonna be good.
Why is it so slow?
Isn't that just a lovely sound?
Don't you love hearing that?
How dare you interfere with the mining business.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
I'm gonna be ready to disassemble it in case we have an emergency.
Okay, now we need to...
Oh!
I was about to say, now we need to check the chests if there's any coal.
But there's some right here.
Bam!
Oh, yes.
Like the game knows...
What I need.
Wait, I need stone.
Why did it choose this one?
Ah, whatever.
Wait, I destroyed a train track.
Somehow.
Oh, it's running away from...
Wait, how is it going on its...
Oh, I guess it must have found coal!
It's a living being!
It found some food and it ate it!
Incredible.
That's actually amazing.
Don't want that.
I don't want this either.
Neither do I want that or this one.
Oh, oh, did I just throw away the rail?
I did.
Woohoo!
Naughty!
Is it just going?
Dang!
Bam, bam.
I love the digging machine.
I can't say that enough.
And look how much space we have in here.
Like, we're never going to run out of space.
Wow, we got a lot already.
One...
Hey, we even got some sink.
That's sweet.
This thing's just going to...
So I wonder if I...
Let's try something.
So I'm going to put a torch here.
We're going to run away.
Let's see how far away this thing will keep...
Like, animating and simulating.
Let's say I just go back to my home, you know, and...
Crack open a cold one.
Hang out on the porch.
Coming back later, you know?
To check on it.
I'm assuming it's going to follow my...
My simulation distance.
It's not rendering the machine, but it's rendering the wall that's being broken.
So we can actually stand here and see when it stops.
How dare you?
I'm observing.
Do not disturb me when I'm observing.
What is that right there?
There's something on the...
Oh, now it's gone.
I did this...
Oh, it came out the other side!
Look at it!
Woohoo!
It's just going, baby!
Now it's cutting down trees.
When is it going to stop?
It's so weird that I can't see the machine, but I can see everything behind it.
Hey, I'm observing.
Get away from me.
It's still digging.
Oh, wow.
What is my simulation distance even at right now?
Video settings.
It's at 16 chunks.
And one chunk is like...
I think it's like 10 by 10 or something?
Close to that.
Actually, maybe 16 by 16.
No, get away from me.
Oh, did it stop?
I think it stopped.
Yeah.
Okay, let's...
I'm going to destroy this guy.
Good night.
Let's move and see when it starts again.
Oh, I can only move slow when...
Shouldn't it have started at this point?
Oh, there we go.
Look, now it's going again.
Aha!
So I guess it just pauses, but it retains its...
You know, whatever it was doing previously.
Sweet.
Don't care.
It's digging.
Maybe we should stop it now.
I mean, it's been doing a lot of digging.
Yo, maybe we can put like a...
There's got to be a way to sort of program it.
With like a timer maybe.
To say like, okay, now turn 90 degrees.
You know?
And then after a certain time...
Now turn 90 degrees again.
Let's see what's happening here.
It stopped?
Why did it stop?
Maybe it ran out of coal.
Or...
No, it should not have run out of dirt.
No way.
This thing is still animating, so that means...
What does that mean?
It means there's still coal in there.
So why did it stop?
Let's investigate.
Deploy the detectives!
Maybe it just stops when you're outside of simulation distance and you have to reset it.
That's the only explanation here maybe.
Oh no.
Oh shit!
Get away from me!
I don't want extended warranty.
Let's just light this place a little.
Look how slow they are in water.
They probably move at the same pace that I'm moving when I'm swimming and try to move.
So the question is, if I push this, is it going to start again?
Wait, what?
What the hell?
That's a new sound effect.
So obviously it's not on a rail right now.
What's the rail situation?
22.
14.
It must be okay.
It's like it wants to go the other way.
Let me put it down again.
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
It's going.
Interesting.
So when you're out of simulation distance, it sort of stops.
And then you have to sort of, you know, redeploy it, I guess.
It's getting a little confused.
But this is cool.
Imagine this train coming across here on a bridge, you know?
In fact, this is going to pass by that village over there.
Yo!
We're going to have a bridge here and then we're going to come underneath with a boat.
Oh, man.
That's going to be sick.
This will be the new memory lane.
I mean, I actually like it.
It also, you know, snakes like the old memory lane.
Biddle-iddle-iddle-in.
Give me that coal.
Give me some stone.
You know what the good news is?
Cobblestone?
It's used in something.
What was it?
There.
So, by having a machine like this, we're getting...
Insane amounts of cobblestone.
And presumably also some diorite.
You would hope so.
Let's see.
It doesn't look like we have any diorite yet.
Is it actually just randomly distributing?
Not really.
It really hasn't found any diorite.
I don't believe it.
What?
How?
Maybe a diorite appears at a lower depth.
That's the explanation.
Also, level 30.
Really should put torches here.
This is a big-ass mining operation we've got going here.
It's so violently, you know, destructive.
And, like, we're bending nature to our will here in a way that makes me a little scared.
It's almost too much.
Hey, wait.
It's...
It's making experience for me, too.
Oh!
It's all stacked up front!
Oh my god!
That is amazing.
Why is it so slow right now?
What have you encountered?
Why are you this slow?
Hey, we got some iron.
Two iron?
That's...
That can't be it.
From all of this, you only have two iron?
Bro, what's happening here?
No diorite?
I gotta plug these holes.
I gotta...
I have to.
Okay, as soon as I come up the other side of this, whatever this is, we're gonna stop digging.
Okay.
We came out.
Is that water?
Oh.
Just block that off, I guess.
Continue.
Oh no!
Uh-oh.
Why does that happen?
Go!
Did we make it out?
Not yet.
Maybe there's like an item in Create that collects experience, similar to how these chests collect items.
Oh, I forgot to test my theory with the toolbox.
But honestly, I kinda like where this is right now.
I think the toolbox is just gonna make things worse.
Okay, we got sink.
It's good.
Nine raw iron.
We're making some progress.
Copper, flint.
Look at all this coal we're collecting.
I'll take this.
God, my inventory is horrible.
Uh...
I'll get rid of some stuff here.
Oh, oh!
We're making our way into something...
...different.
Whoa, wait, what?
Oh!
You!
Oh, dude, for a second, I thought it was iron.
I'm an idiot.
It's not even iron, it's coal.
Man.
The hell?
You know what?
Actually, no.
It's kinda cool looking.
I'll say that.
What's happening here?
What even...
Is this area?
It's already full.
Damn, you're getting a lot of cobblestone out of this.
If only we had diorite, huh?
Okay, we're out, we're out.
Let's just see, uh...
Let's just get a little further, though.
Okay, stop now, stop now, stop now.
Sweet experience.
Don't eat apples.
Don't eat...
I need everything here.
This one I don't eat.
Okay, let's go back with the loot.
It's a long way.
Now it's time to make some, uh...
I need to remind myself here.
Right.
All we need is sink and stone.
And if we have that, we can make a lot of these rails.
So we can make a lot right now.
I think I must have, like, at least a stack of sink.
That I can bring with me, which is like a stack of ingots.
Which turn into practically billions of nuggets.
A creeper blocks my way.
Dude.
There we go.
They found a little darkness, huh?
Also, we should go enchant now.
Now, since I'm here...
Uh...
Honey.
So I guess the way we do this, we're gonna elevate the rails up like this.
And then down like that.
I mean, not over there, but here.
That way we can pass underneath with a boat.
And it's gonna look incredible.
In fact, we have multiple...
No.
This is the only passing.
Let's wait.
Maybe I'll even do, like...
Oh, man.
I am so excited for these trains.
They're happening today.
I know I keep saying, like, trains are coming.
But today they're actually coming.
We're making a whole network.
This is the day.
I should probably do this.
And that.
I'm gonna take this too.
Now.
Yeah, let's...
Oh, right.
They don't sit on those.
The OCD in me is really unhappy with the non-regular intervals of torches.
Wish they were, like, completely regular.
But that would take forever to calculate.
Or count, I mean.
Look, we're ready.
Actually, we gotta make a couple more...
I do have some stacks of rails already.
So we're gonna grab those.
And then we're gonna set the factory to work.
On a lot of new rails.
While we put down the rails we have.
This is the plan.
Where's my shit?
Gimme.
Okay.
First things first, though.
We clean up the inventory, because this is an atrocity.
Absolute atrocity.
I guess we can cook this.
Now the sink needs to be...
Oh, I really wanna bulk blast it.
That's the way.
I also have a lot of coal, which is amazing, because I can fill all of these up with coal now.
Man, what a mining session that was, huh?
Doesn't that feel incredible?
We're gonna give each 32.
Ah, hell.
Let's live a little.
Let's put this in there.
And this one in there.
46.
More stakes.
Give me one arrow.
And...
We need to blast the shit out of this, man.
I gotta do it.
So we currently have a setup here.
For washing.
But...
I can use this.
I wanna set up something right next to it, right?
We need lava for that, of course.
Ah, I need to think.
So I need...
I'm blanking as...
I can't think.
I need a fan.
Fan.
There we go.
You got one?
Okay.
And then I need the uppers and downers.
There.
Uppers.
Where are my downers?
I guess I can turn uppers into downers.
Oh, we have some.
Okay.
I guess the way we wanna do this is to simply have...
Ah, wait, that's not...
No!
Wait.
Maybe this is not possible.
What I'm trying to do.
I need the thing that...
Oh, God.
I need belts.
I need the...
Or not belts, but the...
The sidewaysers.
Is it that one?
Chain drive?
And then we need to move this one over here.
So we're gonna have to do this.
I guess...
Or...
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I have a genius idea.
Dude!
Oh my God!
Watch this.
It's spinning the other way.
Huh?
Lava there?
And how did I...
Uh, I guess I need a, um...
Thingy.
Copper grate!
Oh, that's amazing.
It also has apples and stuff.
I don't really want any of that.
Glass can go away.
Casing.
I'm pretty sure I had more casings.
Hmm.
Maybe I used them all.
Somehow.
It's...
What was I doing?
I was...
Oh yeah.
Right.
Give me that one.
Just one.
And then I need to grab some lava.
Yeah?
Bucket time.
Dude, I used to love bucket time when I was a kid.
Like, one of my favorite things.
There we go.
And then we also need a...
Oh!
That's why I had that on me.
I was like, where did that come from?
Haha!
There we go.
And look at this.
This...
Whatever I put in there is going to get blasted now!
But wait!
How can we make it better?
How do we...
Okay.
So we...
We throw shit in there.
It's going to get blasted.
Now we need a filter.
No, uh...
Wait.
Yes.
I guess.
But I...
I wish I had like a filter for like multiple things.
What am I moving out here?
Oh, I'm moving out here!
It's my footsteps!
Wow!
I just got confused.
No, there's someone else moving.
It's not just me.
There's multiple footsteps in this investigation.
Steering wheels.
Don't need that.
Okay.
What was I doing?
Oh, yeah.
Right.
Uh...
We need...
I was thinking filters.
So...
So item comes in.
Plop!
They got blasted!
So we have to have them not be picked up or processed while they're being blasted.
Let's say they're now blasted.
Okay?
What then?
They are blasted now.
Uh...
I think we may need a, uh...
Funnel.
No.
No, no, no.
Hold on.
Filter.
Maybe this is what I need.
List filter!
Maybe.
Matches items against a collection of items...
Or other filters.
Can be used in filter slots of creates components.
Oh!
Oh, wait!
I just realized how this is gonna work!
So in the slot that you usually put something...
So, for example, before I put in rails, right?
You would put in this item.
And on this list filter, you have a list of items.
It's like an array.
Except...
It's...
Array is not the same as list.
But you know what I mean.
I may actually have this.
I may not have it.
List filter.
Wool and nuggets.
Okay.
Oh, I've got wool for you.
I even got a nug.
Question is, though, do it...
Does it have to be...
Nice.
Okay, so now that we did that...
Now we need the thing that goes down...
And it goes...
And I think I have one of those.
It's a chute.
Methinks.
Does that have a filter thingy?
Does not.
So is it a smart chute?
I may have that.
Shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot.
Then again!
Wait a minute.
Do I want that?
Do I even want that?
Methinks I may not want that.
I'm gonna use a belt.
Because belts are cool.
But belts require rotation, which I don't have.
So fuck that.
I hate it.
Inst...
I hate them moving!
Hmm.
Ah, I forgot what I was doing.
Uh...
Oh yeah, right.
Also, these go over here.
Put them there.
Fucking hell, dude.
Wow.
Uh...
I was doing the horizontal blip thing.
Oh, smart chute.
Smart chute.
I don't think I have that.
What's that?
That's not what I need.
Dude, for some reason, my brain is melding right now.
I'm like overwhelmed.
I need to calm down.
Wait, we have a list filter.
We already had one!
Ha-ha!
Amazing!
Very nice.
Okay, now, put this in here.
What does it cost?
That's expensive.
Mucho expensivo.
As they say in...
Spain.
Uh...
Oh yeah, the electron...
Tube.
Come on, I must have...
I had like a million of those.
I don't believe it.
Is it here?
I made a handful.
I guess I have that.
Okay, guys.
Check it out.
I'm gonna use a funnel.
You can't stop me.
Wait.
There's rotation...
I'm not gonna use a...
Brother!
I hate it.
You know what I need?
I need a goddamn hopper.
That has a filter on it.
Is that so hard to come by in this economy?
Oh, I think I need to make the damn tube.
But part of me thinks I have a tube.
But then I have...
I don't, you know?
So I...
So I don't.
Oh, we already had brackets.
Nice.
Wait, maybe we can actually...
Directly do this.
Even though there's no thing on it.
Oh.
Oh!
Denialist!
Wait, what?
Items only match if their durability enchantments...
What?
Guys?
I think I just...
Dude.
An item sorter is gonna be so easy in this game.
Hello?
We can get that done in like a couple hours.
Tops.
Compared to, you know, hundreds of hours.
Oh my god.
Damn.
But I guess you only have this amount.
But that's...
That's...
That's fine.
And you know...
Who knows?
Maybe it even expands when you fill this out.
Maybe there's like a new row appearing.
Damn.
But it's not gonna go on here.
That's too bad.
I need to make a...
An electron thingy.
We got a polish.
So we need a hand...
Uh...
No.
We need the...
Hand cloth.
The...
Polish...
That thing!
Sandpaper!
I don't have it.
But for that we need sand and paper.
I remember that much.
That's the easiest one to remember.
I must have sand.
I have sand.
But I have too much crap too.
This is not good.
Let's just get rid of this stuff right now.
We don't need to carry around the contraption and all that.
Don't...
Don't need this either.
And we don't need this either.
Or this.
Ew.
Get it out of here.
Also minecarts.
Okay.
Now we need the...
Uh...
Sand and...
Paper.
I'm losing my mind.
I have it, man.
Amazing.
Now we have sand.
So guess what?
Sandpaper.
Now we take this.
We put this in my hand.
We put this in that hand.
And we go...
There we go.
We got it.
And now we combine these two.
Elec.
With the sheet.
Core elec.
Put this back.
Put it there.
Back.
And now we have that.
Which means we can make...
We cannot make it yet.
Because we need a chute.
Or we can make a smart chute.
Please let it be the thing.
Let's see how smart it is.
They're vertical chutes with additional control.
Oh yeah?
How much?
Items in the filter slot specified what to extract or transfer.
Beautiful.
That's exactly what I needed.
Use the value panel to specify the extracted stack size.
Wow.
Redstone power will prevent smart chutes from working.
Nice.
Beautiful.
That is exactly what a man needs.
Exactly.
It's actually uncanny how exact that is.
There you go.
And now...
We're gonna do this.
Watch.
Also, I noticed something in that little preview just now.
It may have one of these little filter thingies on each side.
Which means, potentially...
List filters times four!
Think about it.
Are you thinking about it?
So what do I want to come out of there?
I want...
What do I not want to come out?
Oh, I need to do this first.
So I...
What I don't want...
Is this.
I don't want that either.
Let's see what else I don't want.
That stays in there, huh?
Wait, is this actually consuming?
I don't want...
I don't...
This either.
I also don't want that.
What else do I not want?
That's about it.
I'm happy.
Are you happy?
I also don't want this.
I also don't want that.
Oh, wait!
It is...
Oh!
It's not...
It's not consuming.
Okay, well, there you go.
Items pass if they do not match any of the above.
An empty deny list.
So...
Ah!
Okay, so it's highlighted.
Good.
Wait, I wonder if I can have, like, a cooked status.
Items only match if their durability enchantments and other attributes match as well.
I wonder if there's a cooked status.
I'm just gonna ignore data for now.
But!
It's on there now.
Now watch.
I'm going to grab with my left hand...
Some dirt.
Now look in my right hand.
There's a little die in there.
Now...
I plop this in.
Ah, but wait!
It needs...
It needs to come out somewhere.
If you eat food, it needs to go somewhere, right?
Can't just, you know, go in without coming out.
So here we gotta...
We gotta do something smart now.
So that's gonna plop things into a little...
Uh, you know...
Little container.
I guess I can keep shooting it.
So it goes down there.
Now I need to bring it up again.
I ideally want to bring it here.
Which means we gotta go vertical.
And to go vertical, we need to spin.
We need a...
My shit!
Oh!
Crap!
Oh my god!
My shit was on fire!
What the fuck!
Oh no!
Oh, it's so much too!
I can't believe that!
Oh my...
Wait, are we safe now?
Wait, I had no idea lava could do that.
Okay, I feel like I need to wait around a bit and make sure that this doesn't happen again.
Oh, you know what it is?
It's probably because I had wood beams going down right next to the lava, isn't it?
Oh man.
Wait, there's actually wood here too.
That's bad.
Let's put in something else.
Stone is not gonna burn.
Well, hopefully.
Oh my god.
How long was that burning?
This guy...
I was just standing right!
You know what's funny?
From this angle, it looks like nothing's right.
Wrong!
This looks like everything is handy-dandy.
Like, there's nothing wrong here.
With this.
It's like the game tried to fuck me.
And not in a good way.
I need these now.
I need to make this look better.
Wow.
Wow!
That's crazy.
Hey, at least it didn't destroy any of my mechanisms.
That's something.
It's actually...
It's not that bad.
Now that I look at it.
Oh no!
All my bookcases are gone!
Oh, but I have plenty of books.
We're totally chilling.
It's no problem.
It's fine.
Wait!
Didn't I have a chest with things in it?
Oh, they're still there.
Whew!
Thank God.
I cannot...
Okay, let's just check.
Nothing's going wrong here?
Okay, looks fine.
And I guess this means glass can't burn.
Neither can bets.
Nice.
Okay, that's good to know.
Oh man.
What a bummer.
We have to put down extra light here just to make sure no monsters are wandering inside now.
What a disaster.
Okay, that should do it.
Man, that's what happens when you play with fire.
Gotta be careful.
Anyway, what I was saying was spinning to go up.
We need a fan.
Which I may not have.
Because I think I only made two ever.
Yeah.
Hold on.
Fan.
I need to look at the ponder on this.
Right.
Wait, what's this?
Oh yeah, okay, okay.
We know this.
Is it not going to show me like...
Wasn't that like a vertical?
Maybe it was chutes.
Chutes had like a thing.
Let's see here.
Yeah?
But they come from up and go down, right?
I have a great idea.
But let me have the idea in a moment.
There it is.
Super easy.
Yep.
Oh wait, you need...
Shit, I think I may need one of these then.
Oh no!
Well in that case...
What is the point of this smart chute anyway?
I could have just not used it then.
Kidding me?
Unless I do a hopper.
I don't know if that...
Will that work?
I have an idea.
No, uh...
This one?
So let's say now that...
It's got...
This is a chute!
Yeah, there's a hole.
It's gonna fall down.
So we hopper from here...
Into another chute.
Or I guess ideally...
We hopper one more in that direction.
Here.
Oh!
We're looking at!
Cool.
Hopper!
Oh, I need one more then.
My washing machine is making...
Hell of a lot of noise in the background.
Let's try it, shall we?
Let's try it!
Let's just have a quick test.
As soon as that's blasted, it's gonna go in.
Unless...
Wait, unless it already sort of...
Wait...
What?
One more.
Nice.
I guess I just picked it up when I destroyed it without realizing.
Okay, and then...
It's gonna go in here.
And then we're gonna have a fan right there.
And the fan...
I think it needs metal for that.
Because we need a...
Propeller.
She...
Oh, that's actually good.
Except for the alloy part.
Oh god.
For the alloy, I'm gonna need andesite.
For andesite, I need diorite.
And...
Cobblestone.
There.
And then we needed...
These, I believe.
Alloy.
Why can't I make more?
Oh, I just didn't have...
Wait, what?
Oh, okay.
There we go.
Now we have seven of those.
And the propeller needed one of...
Uh, these.
I'm going all in on fans today.
Oh, but wait a sec.
This...
This bastard needs to spin as well.
How do we bring that over?
I guess we have spin here.
But that's in the wrong direction.
Man.
Is that spinning?
Did it...
Ooh.
Ah.
God, man.
There's just no easy way to bring things up, is there?
And again, we do have motion down here, don't we?
Maybe I can...
Grab the...
Oh, I'm going to grab that over there!
I'm a genius.
Hey, hey!
Oh, it's beautiful!
This is real spaghetti code.
Just the way I like it.
Mmm...
And I needed an upper and a downer.
No, just a downer, actually.
Which I put where?
Ah, it's pain!
We got it.
One, and then we need a...
Vertical?
Just bring them all!
You can never have too many.
I'm so glad I made a shit ton of those, actually.
This is actually so dope, isn't it?
Right, actually.
We gotta go...
One down.
Here.
Or, do we?
Yeah, we do.
We do.
Wait, does this even work?
I don't even know if this will successfully bring things in, but we'll find out, I guess.
Do you know what?
You gotta be kidding me.
Because I need to grab it from below?
Is that working?
There we go!
Good!
Good, good, good, good.
Also, I should do this.
Much better.
Keep forgetting that's the functionality.
Ah, here we're gonna need...
Oh, I did it again, didn't I?
Normal gearbox.
Vertical gearbox.
Fan!
Where are you?
Tell me I didn't drop it or something!
No.
Oh my god, where the hell did I leave it?
Oh, it's right here.
Ha ha!
Thought I lost it.
There we go, we got motion.
Now, for the big...
moment.
Will this transfer to there?
This is a big question.
I think it did.
Yeah!
It's working!
Oh, that's so cool!
Let's put a chest!
Surely it'll put it in the chest, right?
Let's see now.
Okay, I...
Uh...
I need something to cook.
Let's grab this.
Dude, I'm so excited!
Surely this will work.
Oh!
You know what the bottleneck here is?
It's actually the hopper.
Because all of these get cooked at the same time, and then the hopper is slowly...
trickling them.
Mmm...
I don't like that!
I would love for this to be instant.
So I guess...
I mean, we do have motion here now.
So why not just...
Yeah.
You know what?
Fuck these.
We're going for belts.
And then we're gonna grab motion from over here, because we got it now.
We can grab it from there, even, and bring it...
Oh!
It's almost too perfect!
It's perfect!
Ah, wait.
Yeah, it's perfect.
It is perfect.
It's actually wonderful.
Oh, dude!
Dude, doing stuff like this...
is some of the most fun ever in Create for me.
I love this sort of thing.
So we bring this over now.
Let's hope it moves the right way.
I guess we'll find out.
Oh my god, it's spinning the wrong way!
Why you gotta be like this?
Why can't you just be normal?
We gotta reverse direction.
Wait, let me think.
Yeah, it's spinning the wrong way.
Ah...
That would mean...
I'll see it...
I'll know it when I see it.
It's not a clutch.
It's a, uh...
shift.
Do I really not have that?
Cockwheel redstone dust.
Oh my god, please stop.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
I have a boat on me for some reason.
Rails.
I guess I need the rails.
But not right now.
No, no, no, no, no.
Okay, now.
Cock's.
Let me just make three, actually.
And redstone dust.
The problem with this is we need a little bit of power, so we're gonna need a lever.
Oh, I had one already.
Sweet.
There we go.
Actually, I think it's fine.
It's gonna look really dumb, but...
Also, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I'm imagining, like, a big rectangular movement.
I don't know if that's even gonna work.
Let's find out.
The best way to do this is probably to put this...
thing over here-ish.
Barely see.
There you go.
Cover it up.
This is not gonna work, is it?
Let's see.
Oh, wait a sec!
This is totally fine.
We don't need...
Oh.
We're chilling.
Now we need a filter here.
What is that down there?
Oh, that's the fan.
Or not a filter.
We just need a, um...
Horizontal chute.
There's a word for that.
Here I go looking again.
There we go.
Oh, it's a funnel.
Right.
Funnel.
Funnel time!
We're almost home.
That should do it, man.
I think we have achieved...
The impossible.
Now, obviously, this needs to be more pretty.
So the way we make this more pretty...
Is...
We simply...
Oh...
I have an idea.
Ah, but wait.
That was essential here.
I didn't realize that was a vertical gearbox.
Whoops.
Okay.
Ideally, I want to sort of...
Actually, let's just double-check this works before we do anything else.
This should work.
Let's put in a lot.
And the good news is about this new design, it's gonna cook everything at once.
And it's gonna deliver everything at once.
Guys...
We have an ultimate blaster now.
Are you...
Do you even realize how big this is?
We're gonna save so much time.
And you know what?
I do need a rail.
Because I am gonna...
Take all the cookables here now.
Let's put it like...
We can even...
Yo!
We're gonna cook so much!
We're gonna turn all of this into normal stone.
Actually, we're not.
Because we want to combine this with diorite.
Do we have any diorite?
Over here, maybe.
We got nine iron out of this whole mining expedition.
That is...
Crazy to me.
How do we not have more?
And how is there no andesite anywhere?
Did we really not pick up any andesite on this whole trip?
Isn't that crazy?
Crazy.
Like, what?
Also...
Now that we have these big wheels...
I need to see something.
Cobblestone...
If we put this in a wheel...
Okay, so wait.
Cobblestone becomes gravel.
Oh my god.
Gravel becomes...
Sand, flint, and...
Guys...
There is a pathway.
There is a pathway to infinite iron here.
Even this?
I need to map this out.
Hold on.
There is a way.
If we can...
Uh...
Wait.
What did I just say?
Why is it every time I walk in my house...
I lose all memories?
It's every time I walk in here.
As soon as I walk through these doors...
It's like my...
I'm getting sapped.
From Men in Black, you know?
I'm getting neuralized.
What is happening?
What was I doing?
I have no idea.
I have no idea what I was just doing.
Oh, yeah.
I was cooking stuff.
Put that in there.
Oh, wait.
I remember now.
Infinite iron.
Oh, wait.
Oh, yeah.
Right.
Uh...
I need to get...
A list.
I need a book.
Don't I have a book I don't use?
This one I use.
I feel like I saw a second one today.
It's that one.
Where's the one that says I'm a bitch?
Oh, wait.
Was it hanging here?
Oh.
Oh, no.
Ink sack, feather, and book.
I think I have all that.
I may not have that.
Uh...
Ink sack is gonna be a little...
God damn it.
Okay.
Whatever.
Billboard!
What was it called?
Just...
Uh...
Flat panels.
Fucking...
Uh...
It's called a, uh...
Clipboard!
Anticide, paper, plank.
Okay.
Anticide.
Paper.
It was called what?
Wait.
Oh, yeah, right.
Clipboard.
Bro, I swear to God.
Whoops.
Okay.
Uh...
Now I need to write down...
Something.
Oh, yeah, right.
Infant iron.
Hold on.
Watch this.
Iron?
We're gonna work backwards.
Nugget.
Where do nuggets come from, Mom?
I'll tell you.
Wait, not here.
I think it was...
So any iron...
Oh, that's actually...
Yo, that's actually kinda sick.
Just being able to do this.
So every time I come home with extra shit...
So...
Oh, even better.
Every time I disenchant things...
Instead of throwing it away after...
I just put it in the blaster.
Easy peasy.
Obviously, we need some...
We need to put these in the filter, too, then.
But, you know.
That's kinda dope.
I like that.
Um...
But I was looking for...
Something.
I forgot what I checked before.
It was like a realization.
Oh, yeah.
I was looking at cobblestone.
That's right.
So, cobblestone...
If we crush cobblestone, we get gravel, right?
And with gravel...
With gravel, we can make flint.
Okay?
Wait.
If you wash gravel, you get iron nugget.
Wait a second.
The pathway is smaller than I thought.
12% chance, though.
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
This is...
Oh!
Guys!
Cobblestone equals iron?
That's insane!
Oh, my God.
Calm down!
This is what we've been training for.
This is it.
It's time.
Uh...
I have a...
I have a great idea.
It's a really good one.
We don't need this clipboard at all!
Eee!
Um...
Belts?
Yeah, we may need belts for this operation here.
We may need...
Plant.
And...
Also...
Probably...
A lot of uppers and downers.
18.
I'm gonna take some funnels, too, because you can't get enough of those.
Maybe a gear shift.
Maybe even the...
encased chain drive.
Actually, maybe I'll need more.
We'll see.
So we need that.
And...
So let me...
So we...
It goes...
And then...
And then we go...
To the side.
We grab it.
It gets moved.
And then we...
And it goes...
Up!
Right?
It goes up and then...
At the end.
And when it's...
That at the end.
Then after that, we go...
Down.
Sucked in.
And output.
Output...
Oh my god!
That's crazy.
Okay, let's do it.
Let's do it.
But we need another fan for this.
I need...
I'm gonna get all the components.
I have everything visualized and mapped in my brain.
Propeller.
Which needed what?
Right.
Alloy.
Sheets.
Prop.
Prop Joe.
Yes.
Just one.
I don't need more.
Give me that.
So...
Okay, so...
Yes.
It is...
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Give me some chutes.
I need more chutes.
Wait!
We're also gonna need...
A...
Flannel shirt.
Or...
Whatever it's called.
Funnel.
But the other funnel.
Brass funnel.
No!
Don't give me electron tube!
Brass tunnel?
Also needs a tube.
Maybe we can do it in a smart way.
Dude...
Where did...
Didn't I just have a brass...
Uh...
Funnel?
Where did it go?
I had it.
It was here.
Where did you go?
I know you're here.
Did I...
Maybe I put it somewhere I shouldn't have.
I'm losing my damn mind.
I could have sworn I had a brass funnel.
Okay, so I was out here...
And I wanted to use the...
Remember, I was looking for filters.
What did I do with it?
Maybe I don't need that.
Maybe there's other things I can use.
Hmm.
Oh!
It's right there, man!
Okay, so now we have that.
Okay, so...
It goes in.
We grab that only.
Nice.
And then it goes on a trip.
It does the thing.
So it's already...
Oh!
Yes!
Ooh!
Okay, so...
But it's also that!
So that comes out.
What do we do with that?
That can be used, can't it?
Flint.
So now we have that.
What do we do with that?
We can do this!
So we redirect Flint.
With some of the gravel.
Maybe.
Imagine automatically crafting fletching tables.
How sick in the head must you be?
To have a factory that produces these en masse.
I'm just gonna say that.
Okay, I got everything I need.
You ready for the ultimate machine?
Extension?
It's spaghetti, but it's delicious spaghetti.
It's mom's.
This is a...
This is a wasted funnel.
Excuse me?
What a waste!
The fuck?
Hello?
We just got an extra.
Okay, now.
So that...
That goes there.
Aha!
Wait.
Ooh.
Ho ho!
No.
I'm trying to think.
So it's there.
It goes...
I guess it goes over there.
Wait, why does that go over there?
Oh yeah, right.
That's for the...
Yeah.
Makes sense.
That's for that.
So it goes in there.
Can I somehow...
Intercept?
Is there an intercept mechanism?
You know what I need?
I know what I need.
Watch this.
Wait, what?
No.
Stop doing that!
The fuck?
It's not what I need.
I need...
I need the thing I haven't made yet, but I know exists.
I don't even know.
Is it called an arm?
Mechanical arm.
This has to be it.
I want to grab certain things off the thing.
Oh my god, it takes a precision mechanism?
Bro, I'm not rich enough for that.
Maybe there's a better way.
Basically, what I'm looking for...
What am I looking for?
I'm looking for something that can intercept on the way.
And just...
I mean, maybe that is the way to do it.
With that arm.
Oh, wait!
I know!
Maybe I know.
Ah, but then we need another chute.
Nah.
Don't like that.
I wonder if there's a way to split...
Actually, let me look at this.
Show me a way to split.
Whoa.
Oh, right!
I actually forgot about that.
That you can do that.
That's cool.
Not what I'm looking for, though.
Let me look at this again.
No, I need to look at the funnel.
It pulls items?
Wait, really?
Wait, this is a funnel and it's going up?
I think this is it.
This is what I need.
Placed normally, it pulls items from the inventory.
So why the hell am I using a fan to pull items up when I can just do this?
That's crazy to me.
Hello?
What prevents me from just using a chest down below?
And then just pulling it up with a funnel.
This is blowing my mind right now.
And then I will have an extra smart chute, I guess.
Smart chute and I can use that.
So there is a way to do this now.
I saw it.
Wait, what?
No, no, no.
This.
No, this here.
So we basically go into a chest, we come out the other side, and on top we have a...
Ah, but can we filter from that?
Oh, but we do have a smart or a brass funnel.
If I put that here...
Oh!
Ooh, I figured it out.
We got it, we got it, we got it.
This is how you split.
Now the question is, where do I want to...
I think I want to pull over here.
Ah, but no, that's too close, maybe.
Like that.
Now I use the smart.
There.
It's going to pull it up.
Haha, it's so dense!
It's so amazing.
I guess I just put a...
Ah, but this is getting a little dense.
A little too dense, maybe.
I can do this earlier.
We don't have to do it here.
Yeah, we don't have to do...
Don't, don't get processed.
We can do it like...
Here.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
That's actually amazing.
Then we go out one side like this.
Come out like that.
Oh, yeah.
Ah, but then we...
Then we also have a problem with the floor.
Don't we?
Unless...
Ah.
Unless there's like a priority going on.
Let's experiment.
Okay.
Now, now I'm gonna say...
That what I want from this...
Is going to be gravel.
Okay?
Let's see if that picks it up before anything else.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Oh, my God.
Gravel.
Do I...
Do I keep that?
I keep some.
Or even better.
Let me just put in some stone, I guess.
Fuck.
God damn it!
Okay.
Watch.
Oh, wait.
Unless it already did everything.
What?
Did it not fall in?
Wait, what's going on?
Try that again.
Oh, shit!
It's going too far.
Well.
That's not good.
Yeah, there was.
Is that what we did?
Like, how on earth?
Ah!
Why?
What was it hitting before?
I'm confused.
There was nothing in the way before.
Maybe this is not a good way either, letting it fall naturally.
Maybe we need to...
I mean, let's just put it into a chute.
Isn't that easier?
No, actually, one higher.
Oh, but that's going to get crushed, I think.
Oh, nice.
Go outside.
Dude, I'm doing so much create right now.
I'm a creator.
Boink!
And then we have a little funnel.
Better, huh?
Now it's guaranteed to go straight down.
Let's try again.
In.
Yes!
It's getting crushed.
Let's see if gravel comes out here.
And not there.
Beautiful!
Oh, it's actually too perfect.
I can't wait for the...
On the other side.
You'll see what I mean.
Oh, yeah.
Where's the water?
There.
What's it like?
Here.
How many?
Uno, dos, tres, cuatro, cinco.
Okay.
But how many over?
I didn't count that.
One.
Okay, it's like here.
One, two, three, four...
Oh, no, they're going to fall down on me.
Please don't do that.
That will make me very sad.
Dude, I kind of want to utilize the flow trademark.
But maybe not.
Tell me it's going...
Is it going the right way, please?
Yeah!
That's what I like to see.
Can you put it where I want it?
Thank you.
Like, every configuration imaginable, except the only one I need.
The game has a weird tendency to do that.
Then we put...
This one there.
There.
Wait, why am I doing so many turns?
This is inefficient.
Ew.
Boo.
Let me go back here.
Nice.
Get rid of that one.
Put it there.
This may not be able to reach.
It's quite far away.
But let's see.
Wow!
Okay.
Sweet.
No, it's spinning wrong.
I hate it when it spins wrong.
There we go.
It's not the prettiest thing in the world, okay?
I understand.
Now, to do this properly...
At the end, we're gonna need...
Wait a sec.
Items will rise to the surface naturally.
Oh my god.
Is it really that simple?
It may be that simple.
We don't even need a fan over here.
Yo.
All we need is a chute.
Amazing.
Also, go to bed.
I think I accidentally put chutes in here.
No way I used them all.
Maybe I did.
Oh, iron.
It's the thing I have now.
Nice.
Ah, but we need sheets of it.
Good thing I have a press ready out here.
Look how fast it's pressing, too.
Thank you.
I got 12 of them.
Now, that goes over there.
This is gonna come through here.
And it's gonna go like...
Through there.
And when it reaches here...
When it reaches there...
Actually, when it reaches there...
Hey, this is...
This is sweet.
Wait, why is it...
How did I make it not flow before?
Wait, that's...
That's actually...
Somehow, I made it not flow before.
Anyway, it really doesn't matter.
So, it comes here.
And then, back here.
There's going to be a chute.
Right...
Oh, I went too far.
The chute is gonna be right...
There.
Yep.
Yep, yep, yep.
And then, we spin it.
Not that way...
Oh, wait.
I guess I can...
Let me try this.
There we go.
Better.
Oh, wait.
Uh...
Did I throw that?
No, that came out of cobblestone, I believe.
Oh, we...
So, okay.
I thought I put a filter on that.
I don't see it anymore.
Whatever.
Funnel.
Okay, now.
Oh, it just doesn't show when you're far away.
Interesting.
That's weird.
Right?
Well, this should work now.
So, check it.
I'm gonna throw in some...
Actually, let me just do this manually right now, just to see.
I think it was on there.
Will it get washed?
Oh!
I know why.
The chute goes down.
We need a funnel.
Whoops.
I get it.
Yeah, I look, they're just sitting there.
Try again.
I think it...
went on.
Oh, no!
Wait, why?
Why?
Oh!
I see...
Oh, I see.
I see.
I think.
Where did my...
thing go?
Now we do this.
Oh, wait.
Now it's, like, weird.
There's almost no space here now.
Is that gonna work?
Oh, fuck.
Oh!
Is it being washed?
It's a particle of...
Okay, so now it's washed.
So now we gotta bring it...
Wait, this is a mess?
So it's...
Hmm.
I mean, okay.
It's working.
It's...
So let me just pull in a bunch of cobblestone.
Just to illustrate here.
Here we go.
Cobblestone...
Gets thrown in here.
This is all gonna get crushed now.
And all the...
gravel that comes out is only gonna come along here.
Fuck!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I have a fix.
I have a fix for this.
We need another list filter.
Actually, maybe we can just have a singular.
Maybe this one?
Attribute filter?
Oh, it's wool you need.
Thought it was paper.
New recipe is unlocked.
So I guess I...
Oh my god.
I guess...
Everything that can be washed, I would like to bring along here.
But now I put in gravel.
Oh!
But I would love to just say...
I, like...
I don't want any of this.
I just want it to be, like, no attribute, just deny gravel.
But now that I see this...
This is maybe even better.
Like, we would love to bring everything we can wash over there.
But for now, I mean...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
That's not what I meant.
Delete.
So, I guess...
Was added by Minecraft?
I don't know what that means.
Like, I guess it's, like, a non-create item?
But I guess it is an attribute filter.
Let's just...
Let's just grab a list filter.
Maybe there is no, like, list filter, but just for one item.
You just...
It's the same.
You gotta use them for both.
But now that we know that we can do that, that's actually huge.
The fact that you can specify by that is kind of nuts.
What would I need for that again?
Iron nuggets.
Don't do this to me.
Now we use this instead.
Hey, you know what?
I guess we don't need this one, then.
If we just say...
Oh, wait.
If we just say this.
Deny.
Then it has to go through the other one.
So we put that there.
And then we remove this guy.
Because these are...
Oh, I didn't mean to...
Okay.
Normal...
Funnel there.
Oh, wait.
No.
They need to just stay there.
Ah, the problem is, though, they're not coming up all at once.
They're coming up one by one.
Are they?
Wait, why did that come up after...
Wait, this doesn't make any sense.
Maybe it ran out of space?
Maybe...
Oh.
There's no space for it, I think.
It's like a physical block right now.
For the items that try to come out.
Also, my andesite thingy.
Did it go in the chest?
Probably went in the chest, didn't it?
There it is.
Yeah, you see?
As soon as the...
Yeah.
God damn it, I hate my design, then!
This is terrible.
Wait a minute!
I just had an idea.
What if...
Instead of having this...
This is...
Let me see.
Oh yeah, this is it.
We're just gonna let it flow into water.
And let it rise on its own.
I need a bucket.
What a mess here.
Absolute mess.
Not now!
Basically, my idea is we...
We put something here.
Wait.
Give me all this.
Oh no, I can never get out now.
Never mind, I can get out.
I was thinking, we just sort of limit water to a column here.
Remember just like the flow in the machine in Season 2.
And we just let it flow up.
It gets washed.
And then when it's washed, we have like a...
Funnel here.
That allows only washed items to keep going.
But...
We can also wash on the assembly line.
Right?
So why don't we just pull this further down?
Or we pull this up.
Actually, maybe it's better to pull it up.
Pull it up to here.
Ah, but it is kind of cool to have it washed on the ground.
Like real life.
You know, having like a wash area.
It's much cooler to have it on the ground.
Like something everyone knows.
Oh, I put them all away now.
This inventory has been bugging me the entire time.
What do I really not need?
I don't need this.
I don't need this stupid flint.
This gravel.
The wool.
Freaking nuggets and the hoppers and the...
Torches even.
Nuggets.
Sticks.
Wood.
Ugh.
Dude, we don't need a bow right now.
Don't need the compass either.
Or the toolbox.
No more chutes.
I can never find my uppers and downers.
They're just constantly moving around.
In the world.
There.
Fuck.
We don't have room for this now.
Oh my god.
One further.
Oh, it's a mess.
It's a mess.
And then we have one of these here.
No.
Fuck.
I don't know.
Pull that over here.
Good.
Very good.
Now it gets...
It gets washed now.
Fan.
Oh my god.
No way.
It's sucking now?
Are you telling me I could have done it along here now?
Wait.
Does this work?
I can't get out.
Wait a minute.
Oh no.
No.
Don't do it to me.
Get rid of this.
I'm losing my mind.
I have water.
It actually works, dude.
Oh my god.
I can't believe it.
Fuck.
Bring it back.
Here.
And then this guy.
No.
Stay there.
For now.
Hoi yoi yoi.
No.
Yes.
There.
And now it's gonna get washed.
But is it smart enough to know that it stops then?
Until it's washed.
Also, take this away.
Let's figure this out.
We may have to extend the belt.
That could be the issue here.
Testing purposes.
Oh no.
God damn it.
It's pain.
Okay.
Here we come.
You ready?
Go.
No!
It's a lie!
Why do they lie to us?
Oh my god.
It's not stopping.
Okay, you know what?
I guess it's fine.
Because what we're gonna do is this.
This is gonna be pulled in here.
And then we're gonna have basically the same setup as we have here.
With a smart chute.
Or maybe not even a smart chute.
Maybe just... a funnel on each side.
But how does that work?
Does that even... does that even work?
How'd that work?
Do they go like... wait...
So, we pull a... like, let's say we do that.
Then it's gonna get washed.
And then here, smart chute, we extract.
When it's done washing...
Wow.
Hmm... wait... is it even getting washed?
Yeah, yeah, it is.
You can see the little effect on it.
Why does it look like that?
Wait, is that also being washed?
We are currently washing the iron nugget.
If you know what I mean.
Not... okay, I guess nothing's happening.
But it's still technically getting washed.
So I guess we... we, um...
Hey, we can have a chest here, I guess.
With a... yeah.
That's actually the way.
So we have a chest with a funnel on each side.
On one side, we're only gonna extract...
I guess we'd also just... for the... going in.
Extract only certain items.
Wait, but why...
There we go.
So we put that there.
There.
And I guess...
Ah, but wait, does...
Is that gonna work?
Or is that gonna block the...
washing now?
Let's find out.
Ah, but I guess we do need the other funnel then here.
Like that.
And then we wanna put in...
that.
Just as an example.
Don't tell me it's gonna wait one by one.
But that's because I threw them down one by one.
So if I go like that...
Wait, they're not being picked up by the belt.
Oh, and now this one's blocked.
So we need a list filter.
How come the stack isn't...
Ah, there we go.
Okay, I just didn't aim correctly.
Yeah, list filter time.
Dude, list filters have become MVP.
They're changing everything.
We should just make a bunch.
Uh...
Bunch of iron nuggets.
Can't make more than one at a time.
Oh wait, I didn't get enough wool.
Whoopsie.
There we go.
Fifteen list filters for the future.
Now we wanna grab.
And we're gonna say...
Ooh...
Uh...
Let's say flint.
Where did my nugget go?
Uh-huh, well...
I have no idea where that went.
Whatever.
That one, and this.
But wait, is that for all of them?
No, that's not what I meant.
Get rid.
Okay, there we go, good.
And then we put this guy, that is now allowing only flint and iron nugget.
Or...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Even better.
Is there like an attribute, is washed?
Nah, that wouldn't make sense.
Wouldn't make sense.
Put it in.
So now they go over here.
Actually, they go in the chest, of course.
And then we can have them come out the other side.
And now we bring them off somewhere else.
And that somewhere else is going to be...
You guessed it.
Maybe you didn't guess it.
Did you guess it?
So if...
Last time we came around this way, so we gotta do the same here.
It's even perfectly aligned.
Where am I?
We're almost there.
Too far, I think.
There it is!
That's where we gotta put it!
There.
And then over here...
Uh...
Wait.
Let me think.
I wonder.
Bringing this up.
We may need a fan for this shit.
Aha!
But we got rotation, don't we?
What a mess!
But it's a beautiful mess.
No, it's too far!
That's crazy.
I'm actually surprised.
But now we have a problem.
God, why'd it have to be too far?
It's turning wrong.
And I don't like that.
If that goes like...
We also have rotation there, but that's...
Actually, maybe that's correct.
Perfect.
Uh...
God, I'm so lazy.
Fine.
Oh wait, I can access it here!
Perfect!
I need...
This one.
I was like, I don't wanna go outside, but...
There we go.
If I connect this, I can't go back.
Let's just do this first.
Now, over here is the problem.
So the way I think this works is that I could...
I could put it into a chest...
Wait, this is gonna be here.
Funnel.
Chest.
Ooh, that may actually just be enough!
We don't even need a fan here!
Still gotta get up here.
Oh my god, this is gonna be pain!
I mean...
Don't do me like this!
Okay, fine.
I thought it would...
Wait, actually.
Wait, wait, I have an idea.
It may actually work.
No.
Wait, it may actually work.
How...
Remember before I extended it somehow?
Shit.
Hmm.
If only...
Wait a sec.
Oh, right, I'm using a fan here.
That's why that works.
Shit.
Yeah, okay, fine.
I'll use a fan.
I even have one, I think.
Yep.
We got one.
And then we need chutes.
Which I...
should have.
It was worth a try, though.
So instead, what we're gonna do is...
Fan here.
Vertical there.
That should work.
Now we're gonna have to do this again.
What?!
Oh!
Oh no, my funnel!
See, now I need the bow.
Gosh dang it.
The medicine, man!
Give me the bow.
Kill this dude.
Okay.
This is a little too...
far.
I mean, too deep.
Too shallow.
You know what I mean.
Here.
Vertical.
Boom.
No.
This guy.
There.
This should be good.
I...
Yeah.
Yeah, that's good.
How about...
Wait, wait, wait.
What about my elevator?
Where's my elevator?
You know what?
I'm gonna take the rotation from here.
Yeah.
We can't be crossing here.
Because we have an elevator.
And...
That should be doable.
With a vertical.
In fact, if we just bring it over...
It's at the same height.
We need one deeper.
What a mess.
Man.
I feel like I'm using so many of these.
I guess I also have a lot.
So...
Whatever.
Oh no!
It be spinning wrong!
Why...
Why am I being done dirty like this?
I really don't want to put in another redstone component here.
Ah, there's gotta be like an easy fix to this.
This is the worst spaghetti I've ever seen in my life.
There's no sauce on it.
It's just ketchup.
If I bring...
Wait.
Am I not eliminating one step here?
This looks so dumb.
Nice!
Oh wait.
I think I went one too deep.
Like that.
And then...
We fan it.
Then we connect these.
And that's gonna go into a chute.
In fact, two of them.
There.
And now before I connect...
Let me get into a good spot.
Funnel.
Boom!
That's it.
Now we get out.
Nobody sees it.
So wait.
Check this out.
There's no...
Iron...
Nuggets in here.
Right now.
Are you ready for the ultimate...
Uh...
Passage here.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Cobblestone.
Watch this.
The ultimate test.
I hope I did everything right over there.
Let's see.
It goes in.
It comes out here.
Into the funnel.
It's getting crushed.
Only...
Gravel is gonna come out over here now.
I actually didn't test this.
Okay, that's good.
No, it's doing one at a time!
We need a brass funnel.
Wait, what about the tunnel?
Maybe the tunnel's like multiple.
It's like thicker, right?
Andeside and kelp.
Anyway, this should still work.
Everything we're doing...
Wait, why is this backed off over here?
Oh, because it's being washed one at a time.
Yeah, no way that's happening.
No way.
We didn't even make this yet!
Let's see what it does.
Andeside tunnels can be used to cover up your belts.
Oh!
Whenever an andeside tunnel has connections to the su...
Real shit?
They will split exactly one item off of...
Holy shit!
The remainder will continue on its path.
And I guess if we make...
Brass?
Tunnel?
We can even put filters.
Oh!
Oh, this is much more elegant!
Okay, I'll remember that for the next thing I make, but...
What I have right now is working.
We just need the brass version.
Uh...
Brass is kinda hard to come by, though.
Like, this is expensive.
Then we need quartz and stuff.
And that's like that.
Which I have, but you know.
Make a bunch.
What is this doing there?
Okay, and then we need the sandpaper?
Nope.
Yeah!
Right click.
There we go.
Sand it off.
This can also be automated, by the way.
Let me just put this in a hand.
There we go.
And I think for the...
Two...
It was...
It was iron sheets.
Okay.
That's all I have.
Thanks.
All right.
You know what?
Actually, I totally under...
Sold, or oversold, the idea of this being an expensive thing to make.
They're not that hard to make.
Like, it's okay.
It's really not that bad.
Brass ingots.
Oh, why not...
Let's make this instead.
That is so demon.
It actually is.
Like, that is...
Incredibly demon.
Let's try it.
I need to actually see this...
Again?
Wow!
Okay, so you just...
Keep going in...
One direction.
Ah, but...
The configuration is different though.
Wait, is it?
It's...
It's a little different.
I'll make a brass funnel...
For now.
I...
I don't have the energy to...
Rethink that.
Too much.
I'll make one of these.
We actually get two at a time.
That's...
That's quite nice.
So, this should...
Yes!
Look, it's a stack!
Woo!
Nice!
No!
Oh!
Can I fix it fast?
Oh, it's not that bad.
Oh man, I thought I just...
This was...
Pain.
Huh?
Why...
Why are these different?
Oh, it's because I have it in a...
Okay, there we go.
There we go.
Now, watch.
The final test.
Final, final, final.
V10.
Ultimate.
No more.
.pdf.
Here it comes.
Cobblestone.
Full stack.
Ready?
Boom.
Full stack.
Coming out.
Ah, we still have a little bit of a...
There.
They're all being washed now.
And as soon as they're washed, they go in.
Isn't this taking a really long time?
There we go!
They're going!
Flint!
Where are my nuggets?
Why is it doing one at a time?
Oh, I know why.
God...
Goddamn...
And the site!
Man.
When would you ever want that?
Like, they suck.
Nobody likes it.
Ruined the whole experiment now.
There we go.
Fixed.
I'm going to gravel my way up.
I don't even care.
Stay mad.
Let's try again.
And this time, with a fully clean inventory.
Because I'm going to be...
I'm going to be bringing in a lot.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Careful there, Turbo.
Don't scatter your items everywhere.
Wait, this is like a pain in the ass.
Sandpaper has durability.
So if you put that on a...
On a line...
That's going to be...
Pain in the ass to maintain.
Unless there's a way to...
Constantly refresh it or repair its durability or something.
The kelp is over here.
Fuck it, put that there.
Okay.
Are you ready for the ultimate washinging?
I need my thingy first.
Traption.
Whoo!
That's a lot.
Dude, imagine already!
Putting this...
No wait, nevermind.
Nevermind.
It's two grand of an idea.
I'm not ready to share that yet.
Whoa!
Careful!
I wonder how much it's going to crush at a time.
Is it one stack at a time or what?
Let's see.
Maybe after a while it's...
That was one stack right there.
I think it's one stack at a time.
But that's fine too.
I mean, that's fast.
That is fast.
Yep, it be one stack at a time.
I wonder if these will despawn.
If there's too many stacks here.
And they're not being crushed in time.
Because they're technically free-floating items right now.
Let's see what's happening over here now.
Look at my iron.
Iron nuggets.
And my flint!
It's going up.
Oh man, they're being...
It's...
It's not a lot of iron you get out of this, huh?
But that's okay.
I mean, it's...
It's some iron.
It's some...
It's better than nothing, right?
And the fact that we get flint...
Can we not use that for something else as well?
Let's see.
Yeah, if we combine that with gravel, we get andeside!
Whoa!
And with andeside comes all the good things in this life.
Very good.
Or we just mass produce a bunch of fletching tables.
That's also a possibility.
I mean, nobody wants that, but you know.
Wait, by the way!
I need to check something real quick.
Because I think we may have...
Yeah!
Look at that bottleneck right there.
Ugh!
Disgusting.
Oh my god.
Again.
I can't believe it.
Kelp, Brass, Electron.
Oop!
There we go.
Look at that bottleneck.
Whoa!
A lot is ready to be washed here.
You know what?
I'm actually kind of set.
Because, surely...
Like, if I manually throw a bunch of shit in here...
It's like...
They can all...
It can all be washed at the same time.
A bulk washer can wash more than one stack.
So, me thinks...
That the current setup right there.
Right here.
You see this?
It's bad.
And we can make it better so that all of this flows into sort of one area.
Where it just gets multi-washed.
So, we need to let multiple of them pass through.
So, we need...
A multi-pass.
That's what I'm saying.
It's amazing.
Now!
Uh...
Oh, yeah.
Put them down.
I don't want to get...
This is my fear.
I have this fear in real life of getting washed, you know?
So, let's get rid of that.
And...
There.
That's more like it.
Now, as soon as this is done over here, it's all gonna pop out at once.
And pop out at once.
Let's see it happen in real time.
Man, it's slow as hell.
Oh, there...
There they come.
Yep.
Let's have a look.
I mean, that's already amazing.
And you know what we can do, actually?
Before it reaches this...
Chest right here...
We are going to put it into...
A good old...
Crafter.
And turn it into iron ingots.
Maybe.
Or...
We make a splitter...
Or a tunnel.
Right here.
And half of those...
Nuggets...
Go to the factory.
Where we make train tracks!
Brain exploded!
It's all connected!
Speaking of train tracks...
We can make a lot.
Let's just...
Put that to work.
I got a little distracted.
Actually...
Everything I did just now was a super distraction.
This whole thing I just did...
Was not even what I wanted to do today.
Man, this is taking forever.
This is definitely a bottleneck.
Oh man.
I could also just add more fans.
With a belt.
With a...
You know.
But if I do that...
They're still going to be backed up though.
Because it's going to wait for the next one to come through.
Unless it's not.
Maybe it's smart enough to go through if there's multiple.
Let me think.
If I do this manually, I would just take my whole inventory and go like...
Cue on everything, right?
And it would all fall into this square and it would all get washed.
So why is that not a thing here?
I think...
It could be a thing.
If I just remove the belt.
Like at the very end.
But then it may not work with the funnel.
Because the funnel is intrinsic to the belt.
So that doesn't work.
Hmm.
I mean, it's not that bad.
Is it?
I mean, we are going to be processing a lot of cobblestone.
And the funny thing is...
Oh, wait a sec.
When we process cobblestone...
That's not even the only thing we get out.
Never mind.
It is the only thing we get out.
Okay.
What if I plop in...
Gravel.
Sand.
Oh!
Oh, that's beautiful!
Sandstone sucks!
But sand rocks!
Oh, that's nice.
I like it.
We plop that in here.
Oh no.
I mean, this also needs a little...
You know, input mechanism that isn't really bad.
But we'll figure that out.
Let's actually fix this floor, because it's driving me crazy.
I've had it.
We had a little incident earlier.
Oh, man.
We're going to have to go crank that shit, I think.
For sure.
The only problem with this setup here is now if I manually just want to wash something real quick, it's not going to be as easy.
But that's okay.
It's not the end of the world.
Now I want to cover that up too.
Also, what's going on in here?
That's ugly.
Ew.
That's more like it.
No!
That was dumb.
I'll go to the river and get some water.
Good excuse for some exercise.
But it is dangerous out here.
There's animals around.
Fresh water!
This looks more like a museum out here, you know?
Like an old train or something.
That's not really driving anywhere, but it's just there to look at.
There we go.
Now, cover it up.
Beautiful.
And here...
Nobody will know what's happening underneath the ground!
Isn't it such a cool feeling knowing that there's all kinds of crazy shit happening all around?
This is a madhouse!
And I love it!
Now, we're not done with wood.
We're gonna have to go crank that shit right now.
Just for a little bit.
It's essential.
C...
B.
Maybe sleep first.
Haha!
This house is not looking good!
It was such a good design as well.
Oh my god!
The roof!
We're gonna have to do the roof again!
Fuck, man.
Hey, what's going on here?
Oh, right.
There's a villager in there.
Oh, that's the...
That's the dude that makes enchantments for me.
I already forgot about him.
Whee!
I really need a boat for this.
No.
I'm doing something else.
Something...
Illegal.
Something that I swore not to do until I had the thing I don't have, but soon will have.
Because I probably will have it.
We're going flying.
Where's my...
Oh.
Whee!
We have arrived at the woodluggers at...
Area.
There we go.
It has mending on it, so if we get experience, we're cooking.
Cranking time.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were chill like that.
My bad.
Come on.
Crank time.
What the fuck is going on?
Why is it not work?
Oh.
I see why.
That's so dumb, dude.
Oh my god.
I can't believe it.
I don't have enough for this.
I do have enough.
What a mistake.
There we go.
Let's try that again.
This time we're going to think step by step.
We're not going to make any mistakes.
And...
Simba!
I'm going to do multiple.
I'll do...
That one.
No.
Oh shit.
You know what, actually?
Why am I not just doing this?
Yes.
That was not worth it.
Ew.
So much wood.
Okay, this was a terrible idea to do it that way.
Let's go over here instead.
I'm just going to take two more.
Wait.
Oh!
I was about to say, not that way, but then I got frightened because I thought I cancelled it, but then I didn't cancel it because it started breaking.
You know how it is.
Dude, I feel like watching Lethal Weapon...
tonight.
I'm going to watch it tonight.
Eat me some Mel Gibson.
Okay, one more.
Uno mas, uno mas.
Oh shit.
Almost messed it up.
Wait, it remembers the amount of crank I put into it.
It has crank memory.
That is actually kinda...
new.
Oh my god, my pickaxe!
I was like, where is it?
Whew.
Disaster averted.
Let's go back.
Ooh, the durability is low.
But it's okay.
Okay, so we got a bunch of wood now.
We gotta make staircases out of some of these at least.
I don't have enough at home.
That's probably good.
And we're also gonna need to strip a bunch of locks.
Yeah.
Reparations have begun.
Yeah, so last time I had wood here.
Which started burning.
Which is, I guess, in hindsight, no surprise.
But now that it's above ground, we should be a-okay.
Ehh!
Okay, fine.
This is ugly.
Let's fix it.
Uh, dirt!
That's what I need.
So that goes in there.
We don't need any of this now.
This was all construction related.
No more though.
Wait, no.
That's more like it.
Did I really have dirt here?
No.
I had stone, I believe.
Maybe.
I'm just gonna put in something.
This is the thing, it's like the-the-the ship of Theseus.
But!
It gets changed every time.
They like sm- You know how they have this...
Thing in Japan?
Where you break a bowl accidentally, right?
But then you mend it together.
With like, uh, I guess, glue or whatever.
And it's like...
The art of putting something back together.
And it looks different than it was originally.
This is what this is.
It is more pretty...
After the fact, you know?
It makes sense.
Amazing.
Good thing I already have this here.
This is a good indicator of where we start.
In fact, I think I went like that, even.
No!
Why?
How?
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
There's more!
Oh my god!
Okay, so y- Oh fuck, I can't have wood there!
What?
Bummer!
Well alright.
Fine.
We're not doing wood.
Whatever.
I am going to do wood at the end here.
You can't stop me.
It's not easy being a Nisman.
Let's put this up here now.
Actually, start here.
No.
I guess the optimal way to do this is to sort of angle yourself.
No, I don't know.
I don't know.
Let's not try and optimize it now.
This is fine as it is.
I really hope I'm making this roof correctly again.
Yeah, it looks fine.
Looks good.
How did this burn like this?
It's like the roof caught fire first.
Almost like the roof is made of wood.
Makes sense.
Whoa.
Actually, there's an argument to be made here why you should never make your roof out of wood.
I feel like I'm learning some of the same lessons that people in real life have learned.
But here I am again making another roof out of wood.
Oh my god.
Completing this roof is actually gonna... it's like mending myself.
All this stress and angst I've had today because of this is going to be healed when this roof is complete again.
No.
Monsters.
Don't care.
Stop that.
Yes, music me.
Music me.
No.
I knew that was gonna happen.
Hey, it's not that bad.
Almost...
Oh wait, did I really pull it all the way out here?
Isn't that a bit too...
What was I thinking?
That feels a little too crazy, but...
Alright.
I guess past me had an idea.
He had a vision.
Yeah.
Vision is good.
I approve.
Oh, but look at this now!
It's still working.
Never mind.
It's just a visual artifact.
Whoops.
Close it.
Ah, but wait.
No, I think I had a...
I had a full-size block there.
That is definitely what I did.
Because that way it looks nice from here too.
Yeah.
Definitely.
Wonderful.
It actually burned away some, uh...
Dirt as well, or what?
What happened here?
Maybe that's how I had it.
Actually...
Wait, but maybe all of this...
Oh, shit!
Okay, it didn't break anything.
I thought it was gonna ruin my entire house.
Oh, man.
That was close.
If that had ruined my house, I would have just locked out of the game.
And then I would have locked back in.
And then I would have angrily continued making the...
Roof.
Oh, yes.
You can't really do anything about that.
No use crying over spilled water.
And there it is!
We are complete once again.
Dude, I wonder how much wheat we have produced at this point.
Imagine.
Oh, it's not even that much.
Maybe it's being backed up.
Oh.
Okay.
So that's what's happening here.
Too many seats.
Oh, my God.
There's a funnel in there, too.
What the hell?
I mean, do I really need all these seats?
Can I not pull these seats into the...
Crusher?
Wheat.
Oh, interesting.
You can put short grass in there.
Oh, well.
I'd rather burn it.
Can I use it as fuel, actually?
Nah, too bad.
That would have been a great fuel source.
There you go.
By the way, I haven't even fed my animals in a while.
Let's do it.
In fact, not even once today.
I forgot I had them.
Come on, then.
Oh, my God.
There's a lot of you.
Bro, what is happening?
Damn.
Exponential increase.
Of animals.
I don't even have enough food for all of you.
I'm sorry.
Some of you will die tonight of hunger.
Some of you will go to bed hungry.
Just thinking about them starving is fucking hilarious.
Oh, man.
Imagine if they, you know, burnt or something.
Anyway.
Why am I having this on my body?
Ooh, look at all this elytra.
It's mending.
Why?
What did I do to get experience?
Huh.
Wait, what did I do?
How did I get experience?
I have no idea.
I did something to get experience.
Ah, whatever.
That's a mystery.
Put them in there.
This one.
Rail.
All right.
So, the roof is not entirely complete.
We still need to finish the inside here.
Oh, my God.
Where's my handlebar?
Did that burn?
What does it take to make one?
Huyand.
Iron handle.
Inside alloy and a nugget.
I got it, man.
Maybe.
I may not got it.
Did I put it in here?
See, why did I do that?
That's...
That's not good.
Already I messed up.
Ah.
I need diorite.
Man, I...
Yes.
I knew I had some.
Jesus Christ.
I have so much stuff.
Whoa.
Nothing I really need, though.
Where's my andesite?
Where's my diorite?
What this...
This shall do.
Oh, yeah.
All I...
I just wanted to make that.
Hello?
Yes, this is dog.
Does it look like a telephone?
I just want to put it up to my ear.
There we go.
Nope.
Okay.
Let's finish the roof.
No!
Oh, right.
I gotta aim at the top one.
Makes sense now.
Now, what's happening here?
I don't like that look.
It's disgusting.
Ooh.
Cover that up.
Why's there...
dirt there?
Wait a minute.
Oh!
Cover it.
Nobody knows.
What happened here?
Nope.
Nobody knows.
Let's fix outside.
Yeah.
Oi!
Oi, mate!
Where are my steros?
Wait, where are my steros?
Oh, they're in my handos.
My other handos.
Hey, we have water here.
Yoink.
That's mine now.
I'm gonna go wash some...
stuff.
Am I?
Maybe I'll wash it.
What if I throw this...
in here?
Am I gonna get a diamond?
Ooh, it's being crushed.
Nothing?
Okay.
I wanna go cook this.
That's what I wanted to do.
There was...
Okay.
I thought I just threw something in there that shouldn't be cooked.
But we're good.
Look at all these iron nuggets we're producing.
This is like passive income.
Guys!
All I do, I go out here whenever I need iron.
I just freaking...
I take all of this.
There we go.
I throw it in the crusher and...
iron's coming out the other side.
It is insane.
Oi!
Wait, why is that not...
There you go.
Get crushed!
In fact, the crusher should always be working.
If it's not working, then we're doing it wrong.
Give me that one.
Up here, I guess that's...
I don't know how I did this before.
Maybe I did that.
Does that make sense?
It's horrible looking.
Yeah, not good.
Not good.
How did I just do that?
I just discovered something.
If you have a hand in your hand and you try to strip wood that's already been stripped, it will apply what's in your off hand.
Look!
That's fucking crazy!
Whoa!
Dang, son!
New tech discovered.
I don't know how I'm gonna use it, though.
It's not...
very useful.
Oh, that's what I need here.
And then, right here...
Oh, did I have something?
Oh, I probably had this set up, didn't I?
Yeah!
That's what was missing.
Beautiful.
And now we just throw it in there.
Amazing.
Kinda wanna put a...
Oi!
I have a great idea, guys.
A really good idea.
I'll show you.
We need a...
Oh, god.
I need to find it.
It's a way to immediately just...
everything.
It exists.
I even recognize its shape.
There it is.
The item hatch!
Alloy and iron trapdoor.
And I guess for iron trapdoor, I would need iron?
Huh.
Beautiful.
Alloy.
Okay.
So now...
I guess what we could do...
I'm trying to think.
Um...
It needs to be deposited quick.
It's like...
And this one...
So we funnel down...
And chest...
We do a chest...
I'm a...
Whoa!
Hold on.
This is actually...
Wait.
I regret...
You know how scary this is?
If I accidentally click that...
Everything in my inventory now...
Is being crushed.
Maybe that's...
Pushing it too much.
That's a little...
Too scary.
So instead...
Let's just...
You know...
Manually deposit into this thing here.
And that's...
That's still gonna be fine.
Oh shit.
There's no room.
We do it here.
Nice.
I need to flap some more.
Okay.
Now...
Whenever we want to do something...
I mean...
That's pretty fast.
Yes, it's not a full stack at a time.
But...
Are they not gonna...
Clump up somehow?
Oh...
I can't see it anymore, I guess.
Fuck.
I'm actually not sure if this is a good idea.
This may actually slow down significantly.
I mean...
It's still fast.
It's fine.
Now I want to cover this entire thing up.
Because it's a little...
Ugly.
Dude, I've gotten so much mileage out of these trapdoors I made...
On the first day.
Oh my god!
It's amazing.
Actually, we can make it better.
That's not better.
That's worse.
There's a way to do this better.
Perhaps.
What do I got?
What about some slaps?
You know what?
I like it.
I'm happy.
I am.
Okay, we're getting a lot of flint here.
Way more than I thought I would.
Hot damn.
But that's good.
Flint is good.
Because we can combine that.
We can combine it...
With gravel!
Oh shit, wait.
Flint?
Oh.
Maybe we redirect half of what goes into the washer.
I guess there's some math involved here.
Because the one half that goes into the washer is producing the flint used together with the half of the gravel.
But I guess you produce a lot of flint.
Yeah.
And we already...
Oh no, no.
It was a...
It was like a press animation.
Right?
So, andesites?
Yeah, it was this one.
So, I guess you have lava in here.
Compacting.
You put flint in there and gravel.
And it becomes andesite.
Is that easily doable right now?
I guess we can redirect the flint that comes out.
Here.
The filter.
Bro, this is crazy.
It's actually wild how much fun gameplay is emerging from these not that many new items.
You know what I mean?
Like, it's the whole idea behind all of this and the way you come...
For example, the crushing wheel has suddenly turned everything into overdrive.
In terms of, uh...
All the things you...
That you want to do with the components that are added in create.
Right?
Because now that we have the crushing wheel...
You can suddenly use these components in different ways and you want to bring them together.
Oh my goodness.
I have way too much flint.
Oh, that's a dirt box.
I guess I'll put some here for now.
It's okay.
We can make some...
Ingots.
Nice.
In fact, this thing here...
The item hatch is a...
It's kinda scary.
This is the best thing to use, by the way.
If you want to sort items.
You put this in.
They get sorted.
By list filters.
All the way through.
Into their own little lanes.
And they go to boxes.
That's the way to make the...
The item sorter.
Yeah.
So that is...
It is actually good.
There's a good use for it.
Just not yet.
Soon.
Clipboard on the wall.
Trap doors.
Wood.
And we're done with the reconstruction here, right?
Everything's repaired.
Oh, right.
Let's make the...
Book...
Shelves again.
Because I need to enchant.
I think we need...
What do I need?
This...
Shelf.
Yeah.
So let's just make a couple more.
I think that may be enough.
Gonna make it look nice.
I kinda want more.
Have some up here.
Maybe like there.
I like it!
Okay, let's check enchantments.
It's gonna be a good one.
So there is one thing I did want to check, but I forgot what it was.
Also, I'm gonna use this here for...
Illustrative...
You know...
Decoration purposes.
I kinda like this.
Like, you stand on this to enchant.
It's like the one at the...
Whatever the hell it is in public.
Stand here in line, you know?
You stand here and you get ready to enchant.
Looks good.
I wanted to enchant...
Perhaps...
A pickaxe.
No, no, no.
Not a pickaxe.
A book.
That's what it was.
I also needed the blue stuff.
Ah, wait.
Shit.
I can't...
Oh, man.
There you go.
Fortune 2?
That's not bad.
26.
Shouldn't this say, uh...
30?
At least?
We may need more bookshelves.
I don't know if we have enough.
I think I need to put them in the corners, actually.
I did omit that.
Actually, uh...
I do want to keep this.
There you go.
Let's see now.
There we go.
Power 4.
Is there a power 5?
Oh, man.
Let's just check different things here.
Actually, I have a pretty crazy shovel there.
It's a good one.
Maybe the hoe?
We enchant the hoe.
Oh, you know what I need to enchant?
Uh...
Breastplate.
So we need diamonds.
Oh, no.
We don't have enough.
Let's see.
Also power 4.
Fortune.
I feel like that's kind of useless on a shovel.
What the hell?
It's all fortune.
I guess it makes sense to just make another power 4 bow.
Um...
To try and get power 5.
So that would be bow.
I need to actually see if I'm right about this.
There is a power 5, right?
Yeah!
We're not gonna do it yet, though.
I'm level 28 now.
Really?
Power 4 as well?
I mean, again.
What is it with power 4?
Punch.
Ooh, efficiency.
We can try and get efficiency 5 on the shovel.
But, wait, I need level 30 and I don't have that.
But let's think about this.
All I need is an unbreaking on my book.
That's really the only thing I want.
Maybe I'll do a dummy enchant?
Brother.
No.
One more.
Are you kidding me?
Yeah!
Oh, man.
Hmm.
I'll do it again.
Hold on.
Capacity.
Oh!
It's gotta be for...
the thing.
Yeah, yeah.
Look, capacity, too.
Makes sense.
What about the diving boots?
Is that gonna have any enchants?
Oh, my God.
My unbreaking is on the wrong thing.
I'm not stopping.
Nice.
I mean, we can combine books later.
It's not very efficient.
But it is what it is.
There we go!
Unbreaking two.
Okay.
Now we just need one more unbreaking one.
And then we're cooking.
You even have feather falling now.
I think that's the one that makes me just take less damage when falling?
It doesn't slow my fall.
Come
on!
Why you gotta do me like this?
Brother.
No!
Bro, this is...
It's not easy, is it?
But, the good news is, we can put unbreaking on the elytra now.
And then later on, if we get a unbreaking two book, we combine it and it becomes unbreaking three.
So, it's actually fine.
I'm gonna do that now.
Hopefully, we have enough experience to combine these two.
Oh, not even that bad.
Fuck yeah.
We're going flying, boys.
And it's gonna be much easier to level that up again.
Or, I mean, not level it up, but it's gonna go...
It's gonna take longer.
For that thing to...
Fall in your ability.
Okay.
Good.
I think also some of this burned up here.
Right now it doesn't look...
Oh yeah, I'm missing a fence.
That's the problem we had there.
It's like right here.
Nice.
I think I should make a path that goes around my house.
There's that.
Good opportunity to fill out the hole a little bit.
Ew.
We're gonna have to combine all those books.
At some point.
Oh yeah, these two bows we can combine.
Make an even better bow.
This is a god bow.
Ah, I don't have enough.
But wait.
We get experience when we feed the animals.
Let's do that again.
Ooh, that's probably how I got my mending before.
Actually, now that I think about it.
That's the only thing I did that gave experience.
There you go.
Everyone gets to...
Everyone gets to eat.
Yes.
Form an orderly line now.
Don't get overexcited.
I think it's very soon time to slaughter.
There you go.
Oh, I already gave you everything, huh?
And there you go.
Level 8.
You know, it would make sense to wait with this.
Until this bow is low durability anyway.
But.
Power 5.
I'm gonna take that.
Yeah.
I can't wait for that.
That's gonna take forever.
Yeah, this is good.
Then we have...
Copper diving boots.
I was almost about to throw them out.
Anything's missing in here?
Oh, actually, there's something missing.
There.
That's how it was.
I think.
At least.
Now, something's missing up there, too.
What is it?
What's missing?
Is it...
Maybe it is just...
Staircases.
I think it is.
Let's just do a quick fix on that.
I am productive today.
Getting shit done.
Ah!
Can I really not...
Okay.
Much better.
That's why the handlebar is there.
Oh, we're gonna need some stone.
Cobblestone.
Actually, I don't need a couple of stones.
I need just one.
There's no way I ran out of cobblestone.
That's an impossibility.
That's more like it.
Nice.
Ah!
Shit!
I just realized what I did.
I see it now.
This is what I did before.
Of course it's this.
That makes so much more sense.
It looked weird to me as well.
Now I understand why.
Isn't it an amazing feeling just hearing that crushing wheel working?
Hmm.
So good.
Because you know that all that is gonna go down here.
And it's gonna become iron for me.
And iron is gonna make all the good things in the world.
Such as rails.
And, uh...
Well...
Rails.
And a lot of other things that are good.
It's gonna be good.
I have too much copper, though.
Can I use that for something?
Copper...
Like, copper ingots specifically.
Or maybe even copper nuggets?
Alright, well...
What about ingots?
Can I not do something...
I guess I can turn them into copper sheets.
Which is something I will need later.
When I need to make a lot of, uh...
Pipes.
Pipes need that, right?
They do indeed.
Let's just grab a bunch here.
And throw them on the thingy.
Put them on the barbe!
Oh, I can just put multiple stacks?
Oh, no, I can't.
Okay.
I was replacing a stack.
Good.
So that's working.
This still needs some refinement.
It's not as elegant, you know?
Yeah, there's way too much copper here.
I think we gotta turn this one into another smelting box.
And then turn this into a wood box, maybe?
Maybe we have wood over here instead.
I like it, actually.
That's not wood.
This is gonna be the new smelter.
Like that.
And this one.
Perhaps I'll take soft stuff like iron sheet.
Nah, it's gonna be both.
We're gonna do both.
So wood is over here now.
Put them down here first.
Wood, wood, wood, wood, wood.
That's a window.
See, why...
Oh.
Right.
That's why that's in there.
Because I just put them in there.
I would say that's all the wood...
Oh, maybe sticks.
That one.
It's a smelting box, too.
Lapis Lazuli.
We need some light in here, man!
There's not enough light.
Lantern.
Yeah!
That's what I'm talking about.
That's so pretty!
We even have lanterns here, look.
Lantern there.
Let's have another one here.
Near the working area, right?
I may cover this up, too.
Because it's not that pretty to look at.
At this one, at least.
I don't like this freestanding shaft.
That's what people tell me in real life, too.
We don't want your freestanding shaft right there, you know?
I'm like, yeah, that makes sense.
Cobblestone.
That's gonna be thrown in the crusher.
In you go.
And strings.
No, no.
Shit, I didn't mean to string the crush.
Reverse that.
But maybe that's good?
What does that do?
It's probably just gonna destroy it.
God damn it.
Ah, too late for that now.
Well, this is what I mean.
Imagine I had the...
The thingy where you click on it and everything goes in.
I already would have lost everything, probably.
Good thing I didn't do it.
Also, why are these not stacked?
Stack them, man!
Pick axes.
Now, I did just waste all my...
Well, not waste.
I didn't really waste it.
But I used all my levels.
The good news about that is, if I die now, it's not gonna matter too much.
I'm trying to remember where I had this back in the day.
Hmm.
I think I had it on that keybind.
C, B, R.
And then torches.
Now that we have so much coal, right?
Somewhere.
Out here?
Just think of everything we managed to do with the returns on this machine, working for, like, 20 minutes or something.
More coal there.
Even have this stuff.
In fact, I should just grab every single cobblestone here.
And start crushing some shit.
All of this will eventually turn into andesite.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Oh, it's so good.
It's so good!
And we have wood over here now.
That's not wood.
Uh, all this coal we're gonna use with some sticks.
It should be called...
It's melting.
A lot of torches.
Now we have that.
Let's spread the love.
Some here.
Some there.
Just in case we want to blast something manually.
But I guess we don't want to do that ever again.
Now that we have the multi-blast.
Yeah, get rid of this shit.
Boo!
But I do want this here.
Just there, you know?
It's good to have.
That's just crushing all day.
I feel like I need more rockets.
So for that, you need paper.
And something else.
Not to make paper.
It really just is...
Sugarcane, huh?
No other way?
No, I think...
Yeah, we just gotta get...
We've gotta make a sugarcane farm.
Actually.
And it's not even that hard to do.
We just need observers.
Although, I wonder...
Is there an even better way now?
I mean, it was super simple, actually.
With just vanilla items to do.
It's not that hard.
And cobblestone?
Oh, we have a lot of that.
Like, the one thing I have so much of.
Let's grab some.
And what was it?
Redstone or something?
Redstone and quartz.
Let's make, like, eight.
Wait, what?
We just got something new!
I never made an observer?
That's insane.
Wait, why did the cake just...
I know how to make a cake.
When did I just...
Was it on the first page?
Or is it...
It's probably in here?
Maybe?
Show only create.
Because that's definitely a create thing I just got.
I'm, like, convinced.
Maybe it's not.
Wow.
What the hell did I just get?
So, it was, like, a...
Observer with some red on it.
No.
Train...
Wait, Train Observer.
Maybe that was the one.
But I don't think it was.
I'll know it when I see it.
Why did that happen again?
Ah.
I don't know.
It's probably that one we got.
Who knows?
In any case, we got Observers now.
Now we need Pistons.
But I'm trying to think.
So, the way that works, you have a sugar cane that grows.
And when it's high enough, when it grows two blocks, that's when the Observer sees it.
No, wait.
Yeah, yeah.
So, the Obs...
The Observer sees it on two blocks.
And then it gets chopped.
Yeah, yeah.
So, Observer up top, as soon as it sees the second block growth, it triggers the puncher down below, punches it, goes into a hopper, flows along the flow, trademark, into a box.
That's the old way.
Now, in a better way, maybe, maybe it's something simple as...
So, up here, we already are harvesting things, right?
Maybe it's as simple as that.
It's that one.
I wonder, though.
So, this one chops them when they're fully grown.
But...
No such thing with a Sugarcane, right?
A Sugarcane...
Like...
Or maybe there is such a thing.
Maybe a Sugarcane can only get so high, and then when it's so high, that's when this one starts triggering.
Let's...
Let's experiment.
So, plant a Sugarcane.
You just need to plant it next to water, I think?
And that's it.
Oh, I may not even have any.
Ah, damn.
We gotta go catch some.
I need to fix that hole.
It's driving me crazy.
Dude, I just looked over on OBS.
The shit is looking like five frames per second.
Hold on.
Are we lagging?
It looks like a terrible lag is happening.
I'm asking.
Also, my bit rate is all over the place.
It's like red, and it says...
It's like...
Looks like a cardiogram of someone who doesn't have a healthy heart.
Okay.
Okay, you guys are saying it's good?
Weird.
Every single, like, indicator I have to tell me about stream health is telling me that it's bad.
That's weird.
That it's just not...
Oh.
The game...
The game crashed.
You know what?
It's probably a good time to stop anyway.
Fuck it.
Wait, I can't even hear anything now.
Now it's because I muted it.
There we go.
I was actually gonna...
I was gonna stop soon anyway.
This is a good time to stop anyway.
Man.
I actually...
I had a plan at first in the beginning so we started digging this massive tunnel because I wanted to, you know, create the railway through it and I actually already have enough railway, I think, to fully, you know, go through that tunnel.
But then I got distracted by something at home and I started making the...
Oh, that's right.
I discovered the iron thing.
I could make iron nuggets by washing.
Guys, that is like a huge discovery.
If you do that right, you can, uh...
you can produce a lot of iron and with that you can start to really, really boost everything else.
And I also had an idea earlier, I didn't mention it, but imagine you had a train and this is where it all comes back, you know, like full circle.
You have a train that has certain stops where it can deposit items.
It has other stops where you put items in.
So you have the digging machine, it's out there doing the digging and let's assume we have some kind of setup going where it rotates on its own like I talked about earlier and it sort of...
We somehow make it just carve out an immense area, right?
And when it's done, it deposits everything at a certain point.
The train comes by, picks it all up, okay?
It takes all the cobblestone, it takes everything.
It drives back home and when it comes home, it deposits the cobblestone into the crushing wheel.
It then gets dispersed and all the output stuff gets put into different areas, you know what I mean?
Yeah, like a quarry, exactly.
So we have a massive quarry going somewhere and all the stuff that's being dug is being put on the train to come back home to generate iron for me.
The problem with that is though, the train or the digging machine...
Oh, this is actually an issue.
The digging machine is going to be so far away where it's not going to be simulated.
We tested that today.
So we're going to have to figure something out with that.
That's like, maybe just increase the simulation distance or...
You know?
Yeah.
Today automation was on thousand percent.
It's so fun once you start connecting everything together.
Dude, at some point, I was so overwhelmed by...
I had so many ideas that I just kept forgetting what I was doing.
If you remember, that was a certain point where I just kept forgetting what I was doing.
And at that moment, I thought, okay, man.
My appointment on Wednesday...
Part of me hopes that my psychiatrist is going to tell me, yeah, you have ADHD and we're going to put you on something.
Because imagine eating a medicine and having that go away.
That sounds like a dream to me.
I don't know if I do suffer from something, but at that moment, I was thinking that, you know?
Ha ha!
Man, the meds will take all the charm away.
As soon as I get on some kind of med, I'm just going to go in and immediately just create the most insane factor you've ever seen without getting distracted once.
I'm not even going to talk.
I'm just going to be focused.
I'm just going to be sitting there.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Nah, I probably won't.
You're right.
You're on ADHD meds now?
I mean, people have told me that's how that feels.
And you're saying the same thing, so I don't know.
I guess we'll see.
Maybe...
I mean, I'm going there for a diagnosis, right?
She's going to look at me and determine what's going on.
And I'm just going to be honest and tell her about things, right?
And who knows?
Maybe she'll say, there's nothing wrong with you.
You're just, you know, a person.
I don't know.
And by the way, if she says I don't have ADHD, because she's like a real psychiatrist, you know, she knows her shit, allegedly, then none of you are ever allowed to mention ADHD again regarding me.
Because I didn't have it proven by a professional.
There you go.
You can call me something else.
You can call me scatterbrained or...
I don't know, dumb.
That's fine.
I don't think we can accept that trade deal.
Oh, okay.
You need to watch one of your streams.
The thing is, though, there is a certain element of performance on the stream as well, though, right?
Like, yes, I'm just being myself.
But obviously, I'm, you know, I'm more in the zone, I guess, when I'm streaming, you know?
It's unavoidable on some level.
So I don't know if that's a good way to judge something like that.
The best thing she can do is try to put me on a test or something and see if I can do it without getting distracted.
Because that's the thing I had so much issues with during my education.
It was such a big hurdle for me, actually.
To just sit down and study something that wasn't 100% interesting to me.
Because if it wasn't, like, blowing me away in terms of fun, I just had so much trouble doing it without getting distracted.
And then, other times, like, when I do something that I really enjoy, like, I will often forget to eat because I do it so much.
You know?
So, and I've read online, like, this is, like, textbook ADHD stuff.
But just because that sounds like it doesn't mean it is that, right?
I guess we'll find out.
As a streamer, you're absorbing far more stimuli than any of us individual chatters.
Yeah.
I think you're right.
It's definitely easier to just be a person watching a stream.
I mean, of course.
That's why you can have a stream on the second monitor, right?
While you're doing something else.
Which I like to do, as well.
But I am curious, you know?
Like, what it would feel like to just if they're...
Like, that's the thing.
I'm unsure about it, you know?
Like, I don't know if I actually have some kind of problem.
And if I do, what it would feel like to have that problem go away, I, like...
It sounds insane.
If I was talking while playing, I would also miss a lot of stuff.
Yeah, I think you're right.
Talking while doing something really does distract you a little bit from what you're doing.
Because you can think much faster faster than you can talk.
And I think that's also part of my problem.
I have trouble getting my thoughts out into words sometimes.
Like, a good example is when I discover, like, a new item in Minecraft.
Something that can do something new.
Immediately, I get, like, five different ideas for how that can be used.
And that...
And those five ideas are, like, already in my brain.
Hard to get out.
And I have trouble trying to pick one because I get so excited about it as well, right?
And I can't just focus on one of them and get it out clearly.
Memes aside, streaming steals a huge amount of brain budget.
I guess so, yeah.
Especially if you're talking.
You're the most indecisive person ever.
Yeah, I totally relate to that, though.
I understand.
Have you seen the sift?
No.
I don't know what that is.
Show the doctor one of your vods.
Yeah, someone said that before.
I don't think it's gonna be much help, though.
Jesus is gonna think I got the appointment to try and get new subscribers or something.
Just go there and be like, hey, look at my channel.
I feel like that's weird.
My favorite part of today's stream, Lilo Dallas Multipass.
Nice.
I think most of you got that reference.
I think maybe only the really young people might not have gotten that one.
It's like, it's such a classic.
If you're over, I'll say 25, you must know it, right?
Just, I mean, your parents must have shown you that movie then, at least.
My favorite part was the house burning for 10 minutes without you noticing.
Did you guys notice it burning for 10 minutes?
I'm so curious.
Or did none of you know?
Was it, like, at all on screen that it was burning?
No, I mean, like, did you see the burning or did you...
I mean, obviously, you would know since I put the lava there and you saw there was wood, you probably would have thought, okay, it's going to burn because I figured that out today.
But I'm talking, was it actually visible?
You kept walking straight past the flame?
Okay, I gotta rewatch that part.
I have to see your reaction to it.
I have to see that after this.
I gotta...
Okay, let me actually...
Let me see that.
Not noticing the fire.
Hold on.
Now we have sand.
So get...
I make...
I'm just going to pause this real quick.
Guess what?
Sandpaper.
Oh, it's burning!
We put this in my hand.
We put this in that hand.
And we go...
There we go.
Oh my God!
It's what I did the bit with the masturbation as well.
We got it.
And now we combine these two.
Oh, wait.
I'm not even showing it.
Hold on.
Oh, but you can click the...
I'll show you.
Oh my God.
That's amazing.
This is the funniest shit.
Wait, where's the...
I mean, you saw it.
You were there.
You saw it.
Uh...
Not noticing the fire.
There you go.
You can see it now.
Here, look.
Now we have sand.
So guess what?
It's just burning in the background!
Take this.
We put this in my hand.
We put this in that hand.
And we go...
There we go.
We got it.
And now we combine these two.
Dude, how did I not see it?
What the fuck?
That's crazy.
Legitimately had no idea that was burning.
Wow.
That is...
That is insane, man.
Talk about tunnel vision.
What the fuck?
We could hear it for ages.
Oh my god.
That's so funny.
One of the bots available to watch?
It'll probably be up within one and a half hours or so.
For some reason, the Minecraft ones take much longer to upload.
I think, or upload, something about the movement and the way the game looks, it just takes up way more space when you're encoding it into a video.
So, you know, it's a larger file size.
But it'll be up very soon.
For example, games like The Sims, there's almost nothing moving on the screen a lot of the time.
So those bots were, like, nothing in size, you know?
So those get uploaded immediately.
So the biggest bottleneck there is actually YouTube checking for copyright stuff.
So when those checks are done, then it's usually ready.
It's because Minecraft has very noise textures like grass at a distance.
Yeah, exactly.
Or when you're in snow or rain, you know?
Like, there's just a lot of movement on the screen.
And especially...
I move around all the time.
There's almost no times when the screen is just completely still.
Almost every pixel on the image is being shifted at times, you know?
Snow is a recording disaster.
It truly is.
It's like confetti.
Also ruins recordings.
Exactly, Laxor.
It's an anti-compression game.
I mean, I guess it is.
It has stopped me from compressing things in the game so far.
Or compacting, I guess they call it there.
Not compression.
Next stream is going to be Kerbal Space Program, yes.
I am omega excited about Kerbal Space Program.
It is honestly...
I'm just going to call it now.
And I could be totally wrong.
Maybe it takes a nosedive later on.
But if this game keeps up in quality as it is right now, this may be one of, if not the best, single-player game I have ever played.
And I've only played it for like 14 hours or so.
Tomorrow?
No, wait.
Tomorrow is...
There's something happening on Tuesday.
Oh!
I'm going to the movies tomorrow.
And I'm going to hang out with some friends.
So tomorrow is no.
Wednesday, I'm going to the psychiatrist.
But that's early in the morning.
So I think on Wednesday, I would say.
We're going to go watch the new Resident Evil movie.
Apparently it's good.
The vibes are incredible with KSP.
You can feel it.
Yeah.
And I even had a mod made now to make it dark mode.
But in a non-shitty way.
It's just the standard UI, but tastefully done in dark mode now.
So it's...
Oh, it looks so good now.
Looks so good now.
I also...
Actually noticed some graphical glitches I had in the game.
That were due to some bad settings I had.
So now I fixed that too.
So that should also be fixed.
The game should look even better now.
I'm also playing around just for fun.
With like a little mod to create like...
Huge smoke plumes from solid rocket boosters.
It's already looking insanely good.
But I don't know if I want to show that.
I've just been playing around with the, you know, the flea booster, you know, at the launchpad.
Having a lot of fun just messing around with that.
How'd you get that mod made?
Fable and Astra.
Windows or Linux?
I play on Windows.
I'm not...
I don't know how tall I am, man.
I think...
178 centimeters?
I think?
Or like 176 centimeters?
Something like that?
Yeah, it's...
I'm also on...
I'm also just on the pro plan.
So, you know, it consumes really quick.
But the idea is to use Fable for planning the big stuff.
And then having the smaller agents implement it, you know?
You're two centimeters taller than me!
Ooh!
That's not good.
I mean, it's fine.
I wouldn't say I'm that tall.
Especially for a Danish person.
The Danes are very tall.
MCC is great.
What is MCC?
MCC.
What is that?
Is it the Minecraft movie, or...
Oh, Minecraft Championships.
Wait, is it like a PvP thing, or...
Or is it a championship and who can reach credits fastest?
Because the former sounds really...
Not fun.
The latter sounds amazing.
It's a lot of games?
Huh.
Party-style games.
Maybe I'll check it out.
There's MCS...
Man, you guys...
I don't know these, like, acronyms you're throwing at me.
October 10th.
Wait, they have one every month?
What?
Yeah, I'm sure it's fun, Kuroka.
It's just...
I guess it's just...
In my mind, it doesn't sound like something I would enjoy watching or playing at all.
Will you play any Resident Evil games?
I...
Man, I would love to.
But now I feel like I can't.
I can't control my fucking...
Reactions to that shit.
You know, scary games and jump scares.
When I live on...
When I live in the country, you know, with nobody around me for 50 miles.
Woodland.
And it's just me and Jackie out in the snow.
And it's time for horror games.
Okay.
I'm gonna go.
Thanks for watching.
Wow, we were almost at 5 hours with this.
Why does it feel like time is just flowing faster with these streams lately?
Also in KSP, the other day I thought I was streaming for 3 hours?
It was 5.
What's happening?
I'm actually really enjoying streaming lately.
I'm also only streaming right now.
I'm not recording anything other than...
Or, you know, for YouTube.
So it's just streaming right now.
Which is actually kind of fun.
For a bit.
I'll see you in the next stream.
Have a wonderful day.
Bye-bye.